<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Copywrite Matters</title>
	<atom:link href="http://copywritematters.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://copywritematters.com</link>
	<description>Copywriting courses, coaching and content</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Aug 2016 00:14:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Becoming a copywriter begins with great writing. Learn how and save 10%!</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/become-a-copywriter-launch-august-2016/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/become-a-copywriter-launch-august-2016/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 22:00:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=8707</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Have you ever wondered how professional copywriters make writing look so easy? I can tell you that copywriting isn’t easy but when you know the techniques and processes behind writing compelling, profitable copy, it’s a lot less painful. This week I opened the doors of my Copywriting Master Class to accept new students. People who are ready to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/become-a-copywriter-launch-august-2016/">Becoming a copywriter begins with great writing. Learn how and save 10%!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Copywriting-Master-Class-so-good-1.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5873" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/08/Copywriting-Master-Class-so-good-1.png" alt="Copywriting Master Class blog image" width="523" height="523" /></a></p>
<p>Have you ever wondered how professional copywriters make writing look <em>so easy?</em> I can tell you that copywriting isn’t easy but when you know the techniques and processes behind writing compelling, profitable copy, it’s a lot less painful.</p>
<p>This week I opened the doors of my <a href="http://copywritematters.com/learn-copywriting-course/" target="_blank">Copywriting Master Class</a> to accept new students. People who are ready to take the first step to include compelling, profitable copywriting as something they rock.</p>
<p><strong>You don’t have to know anything about copywriting or marketing</strong> because everything you need to know is explained across 16 lessons delivered over 12 weeks … If you already know a thing or two, <em>you&#8217;ll accelerate those skills</em>.</p>
<p><a class="button" href="http://copywritematters.com/?download_id=f1ae7a92e99359475d759876398083ea">Read the detailed course outline</a></p>
<h3>You can save 10% on the price of this online copywriting course&#8230; but not for long.</h3>
<p>I know there are cheaper courses. There are shorter courses.</p>
<p><strong>This is a copywriting course for people who are serious about making an investment … in themselves.</strong></p>
<h3><strong>Is that you?</strong></h3>
<p>If you&#8217;ve been looking around at copywriting courses you will have asked yourself, how can I tell which course is best for <em>me</em>?</p>
<p>This post digs into <strong>what makes <em>this</em> copywriting course so good. </strong></p>
<h3>The personal coaching element is by far and away the BEST part of this course.</h3>
<p>You cannot learn to write profitable copy in a vacuum (unless you’re prepared to spend years gaining experience).</p>
<p>You need to apply the skills and techniques, then you need feedback on where you’re falling short and how to take the extra steps to greatness.</p>
<p>That’s what the coaching element of this copywriting course offers. <strong>You get me as your copywriting coach</strong>, nurturing your skills and helping you to improve much faster than you could on your own.</p>
<p>That’s why I (seriously) limit each intake. Once the copywriting course is booked, the doors close.</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Janistestimonial.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-8191 size-large" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Janistestimonial-1024x576.jpg" alt="Janis testimonial for copywriting course" width="1024" height="576" /></a></p>
<p><strong>Next…</strong></p>
<h3>You get LIFETIME ACCESS to the course content, including access to ALL FUTURE UPGRADES.</h3>
<p>Now that’s a big deal as I update the course content for each release of the course. I add resources, check lists, explanations and examples. As new stories and case studies become available, they get added as well. <strong>And you have access it to all.</strong></p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Melissatestimonial.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-6905" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/02/Melissatestimonial-1024x576.jpg" alt="Melissa testimonial about copywriting course" width="1024" height="576" /></a></p>
<h3><strong>Next… </strong></h3>
<h3>There are NO DEADLINES to get feedback from me.</h3>
<p>Other copywriting courses make you keep up with the lessons being sent and limit how long you have to get reviews and feedback. I don’t like courses like that so the Copywriting Master Class isn’t one.</p>
<p>The upshot is that your experience as a student is the same whether you start on day 1 or day 100, whether you do each lesson as it comes in or you have to take a break now and then.</p>
<p>For as long as the course is running, I am there for you.<strong> I am committed to helping you succeed as a copywriter.</strong></p>
<p>It’s up to YOU how you take full advantage of the opportunities the Copywriting Master Class offers you.</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/Derektestimonial2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-6830" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/Derektestimonial2-1024x576.jpg" alt="Testimonial from new copywriter, Derek" width="1024" height="576" /></a></p>
<h3>The VIP launch price ends SOON</h3>
<p>Seats were grabbed with the first few hours and those new copywriter are already digging in. Registrations are open until August 30 OR until the course is full. Which ever happens first.</p>
<p><em>I only accept a limited number of students in each course so it pays not to dilly dally too much.</em></p>
<p>And when you can save nearly $200 but registering now, well, that&#8217;s serious food for thought.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re still a bit iffy about whether or not it&#8217;s the right course for you, why not <a title="Contact" href="http://copywritematters.com/contact/">drop me a line</a> with your concerns and we can chat about them.</p>
<p>If you&#8217;re thinking of waiting until the last day, don&#8217;t. That day might come sooner than you think!</p>
<p><a class="button" href="http://copywritematters.com/learn-copywriting-course/" target="_blank">Secure your seat now</a></p>
<p><em>Belinda (AKA The Copy Detective)</em></p>
<p>P.S. You can <a title="Reviews" href="http://copywritematters.com/testimonials/">read more reviews here</a>.</p>
<p>P.P.S. If you have questions, check out this schmancy FAQ video I made:</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/qHlUgqzrDPI" width="420" height="315" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/become-a-copywriter-launch-august-2016/">Becoming a copywriter begins with great writing. Learn how and save 10%!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/become-a-copywriter-launch-august-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are you putting up barricades to potential customers? A rant about your website pop-up.</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/website-pop-up-rant/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/website-pop-up-rant/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2016 21:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[case study]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer experience]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[pop up]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[thredUP]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website popup]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=8497</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In case you hadn’t noticed, the marketing chitchat is all about Facebook ads right now. As I spend a lot of time on Facebook, I also see a lot of ads, and you know what? I don’t mind them! I like seeing targeted offers that I wouldn’t see otherwise. I like finding interesting companies that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/website-pop-up-rant/">Are you putting up barricades to potential customers? A rant about your website pop-up.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In case you hadn’t noticed, the marketing chitchat is all about Facebook ads right now. As I spend a lot of time on Facebook, I also see a lot of ads, and you know what? I don’t mind them!</p>
<p>I like seeing targeted offers that I wouldn’t see otherwise. I like finding interesting companies that I wouldn’t find otherwise.</p>
<p>One such company is thredUP. They sell second-hand clothes online.</p>
<p>I don’t have leisure time to shop anymore. I do most clothes shopping online, and being able to reconcile my love of op-shopping (or thrift store shopping for my American friends) with my inability to spend much time in clothes shops is a WIN for me!</p>
<p>I saw thredUP’s ad on Facebook and clicked it faster than my daughter runs when she hears the cracker jar being opened (fast).</p>
<p>And here is when things got tricky.</p>
<p>This is thredUP’s homepage:</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ThredUp1.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8498" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ThredUp1-1024x572.png" alt="thredUP homepage" width="1024" height="572" /></a></p>
<p>Behind the pop-up, you can see hints of their stock.</p>
<p>Sometimes websites present you with pop-ups on arrival. They’re called landing or welcome mats. They might present you with an offer, give you some tips on improving your experience on the website, or ask you to sign up for something.</p>
<p>Like many people, <strong>I don’t like marketing in my face when I’ve just arrived.</strong></p>
<p>When I walk into a bricks-and-mortar shop, I like a hello from the sales assistant. I like to know they’re available. But I don’t like them asking me what I’m after and how they can help before I’ve taken three steps into the store. I’m a cranky pants like that.</p>
<p>The same applies to websites. Sure, <strong>offer to help me, but don’t engage me any more than that until I’ve had a chance to get my bearings.</strong></p>
<p>Assuming this was one such pop-up, I looked for a way to close it. I didn’t see an X or a CLOSE link, so I clicked behind the pop-up to send it on its way.</p>
<p>Nothing.</p>
<p>I clicked every square inch of that screen before I realised that sucker wasn’t going anywhere.</p>
<p>If we take a look at the actual pop-up, we see that it asks me to create an account:</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ThredUp3.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-8499 " src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ThredUp3-1024x665.png" alt="ThredUp 3" width="602" height="391" /></a></p>
<p>Sure, I <em>only</em> need to enter my email address, but as part of the process, I have to agree to receive all their marketing guff.</p>
<p>I could not progress onto the site unless I created an account.</p>
<p><strong>It’s free to join, they say, but it’s not free.</strong> My inbox is paying before I’ve even looked at the stock.</p>
<p>Going back to the bricks and mortar example, this is like the salesperson refusing to let me into the store unless I get their store card. Would you go in?</p>
<p>So I rant on Facebook. Then I create an account. Because I’m interested in second-hand clothes.</p>
<p>My annoyance at having to create an account was <em>lower</em> than my interest in second-hand clothes, but as I scrolled through the clothes, cancelling and unsubscribing were pretty high on my things-to-do-next list.</p>
<p>Now some of you might be thinking, “You created an account, so it worked!”</p>
<p>Yes, I created an account.</p>
<p>Yes, the analysis of conversions registered another sign-up, and if they’re smart, that’s also linked back to their Facebook ad.</p>
<p><strong>Hooray for in-your-face popups…they WORK!</strong></p>
<p>But here I am, more than a week later, the bad taste still lingering so much that I’m ranting about it on my blog. That marketing is <em>not</em> working.</p>
<p><em>A quick aside: My issue isn’t with pop-ups. I actually like well-written, well-timed pop-ups on websites. But I don’t like pop-ups that get in my face before I’ve even had a chance to look around.</em></p>
<h2>Some goodwill clawed back</h2>
<p>The story takes another turn when I receive an email from James Reinhart, the co-founder of thredUP.</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ThredUp2.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8500" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ThredUp2-1024x642.png" alt="thredUP email 1" width="1024" height="642" /></a></p>
<p>Kudos for the follow-up.</p>
<p>Kudos for the offer.</p>
<p>Kudos for inviting feedback and for making the email feel like it came from a real person.</p>
<p>So I replied.</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ThredUp4.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-8501" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/ThredUp4-1024x388.png" alt="thredUP email 2" width="1024" height="388" /></a></p>
<p><strong>This story is ongoing. </strong></p>
<p>I’ll keep you posted on any replies I get. And I do expect one. After all, Mr James said he replies to <em>every</em> email.</p>
<h2>So what’s the lesson here?</h2>
<p>First, if you have a blog, you can rant about stuff like this.</p>
<p>But more importantly, this is about putting yourself in your website visitors’ virtual shoes even it’s just for a second or two.</p>
<p>Do you care more about your subscriber and conversion numbers than you do about the experience real people are having?</p>
<p>Website visitors are worth way more than their email addresses, so consider how you can build trust <em>and</em> get the opportunity to sell to them.</p>
<p>Answer that and then implement it.</p>
<p>I’d love to hear what you come up with.</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/website-pop-up-rant/">Are you putting up barricades to potential customers? A rant about your website pop-up.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/website-pop-up-rant/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy podcast #31 – How to format copywriting for maximum impact</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-31-formatting/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-31-formatting/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copy decks]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[formatting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[presentation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=8442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>How much attention to you pay to how you format your copy for clients? If you just blat your words on the page and think it&#8217;s up to any designers to worry about formatting, you&#8217;re wrong. Lucky for you, we&#8217;re here to help. Today we’re talking about formatting. Some listeners may wonder about this. Talking about [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-31-formatting/">Hot Copy podcast #31 – How to format copywriting for maximum impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>How much attention to you pay to how you format your copy for clients? If you just blat your words on the page and think it&#8217;s up to any designers to worry about formatting, you&#8217;re wrong. Lucky for you, we&#8217;re here to help.</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5440" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Today we’re talking about formatting. Some listeners may wonder about this. Talking about formatting. Not even writing. Just formatting.</p>
<p>But how you present your copy to clients will have a huge influence on how well they receive it. And clever formatting can make your copywriting a lot more readable to the end audience as well.</p>
<p>In this episode, Kate and Belinda share their thoughts and some pro-formatting tips for more readable copywriting.</p>
<h2><strong>Tune to learn:</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li>Why formatting is so damned important</li>
<li>Fonts, sizes and spacing: our recommendations</li>
<li>Clever formatting tricks to give your words more impact</li>
<li>Good and bad list writing</li>
<li>The biggest formatting mistakes new copywriting make</li>
</ul>
<p>You can also listen on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/podcast-31-copy-formatting-important" target="_blank">The Hot Copy podcast website</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And thanks to Christina Tolstrup for your review of the show. We appreciate it!</p>
<h2><strong>Resources from the pod:</strong></h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/what-is-a-copy-deck/" target="_blank">What is a copy deck</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/how-to-write-a-copy-deck-in-five-easy-steps/" target="_blank">How to write a copy deck in five easy steps</a></li>
<li><a href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-copy-decks/" target="_blank">The smart copywriter&#8217;s guide to copy decks</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.copywritingschool.com.au/shop/copywriting-deck/" target="_blank">Buy a copy deck template</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/f-is-for-user-friendly-copy/" target="_blank">F shaped pattern article</a></li>
<li><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Interrobang" target="_blank">What is an interrobang</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sumome.com" target="_blank">SumoMe</a> (Belinda&#8217;s heat map widget)</li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-31-formatting/">Hot Copy podcast #31 – How to format copywriting for maximum impact</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-31-formatting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 no-fail tricks to writing customer-centric copy (that doesn&#8217;t miss its mark)</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/customer-centric-copywriting-tips/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/customer-centric-copywriting-tips/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 05 Jul 2016 21:40:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=8394</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When you’re writing marketing collateral, from website copy to printed brochures, it’s pretty normal to start with what you know. You. But if you’re not careful, you’ll end up sounding like a one of those annoying dinner party guests that just won’t shut up about themselves. It’s all me me me ….. Enough about me. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/customer-centric-copywriting-tips/">5 no-fail tricks to writing customer-centric copy (that doesn&#8217;t miss its mark)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/customercentricbloggraphic.jpg"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-8396" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/07/customercentricbloggraphic.jpg" alt="Customer centric blog image- allow images to see it!" width="527" height="690" /></a></p>
<p>When you’re writing marketing collateral, from website copy to printed brochures, it’s pretty normal to start with what you know.</p>
<p>You.</p>
<p>But if you’re not careful, you’ll end up sounding like a one of those annoying dinner party guests that just won’t shut up about themselves. It’s all me me me ….. <em>Enough about me. What do you think about me?</em></p>
<p>You know the type!</p>
<p>If you want to write copy that <em>really connects</em> with people, so much so that they actually keep reading, you need to make them part of the story.</p>
<p>This post covers five no fail ways you can transform your copywriting from a mega phone blast to your market to an intimate chat with your customers.</p>
<h2>1. Walk a mile (or 2) in your customers’ shoes</h2>
<p>Be as literal as you need to be to face the same challenges and work out what it is your customers really care about. Don’t assume you know and just pad your copywriting out with <a href="http://copywritematters.com/why-10-dollar-words-make-your-copywriting-suck/">buzzwords</a> that sound good.</p>
<p>Here are <a href="http://copywritematters.com/define-target-market/">23 answers you need to define your target market.</a></p>
<p>If you’re a copywriter writing to someone else’s target market, this list will still help you to get into their headspace. The most important part of understanding your reader is to think about the why behind their actions – <a href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/">their motives</a>.</p>
<h2>2. Talk about benefits not features</h2>
<p>You’ve probably heard this before but it can be harder than you think.  A little copywriting trick I use is to imagine a stony faced customer responding to my explanation with a “so what?” … again and again and again.</p>
<p>I say:  My copywriting has a very conversational tone to it</p>
<p><em>So what?</em> Well that means that your marketing will feel more approachable</p>
<p><em>So what?</em> Your target market will be more engaged with your key message</p>
<p><em>So what?</em> More people will be persuaded to hand over their cash</p>
<p><em>So what?</em> You sell more stuff and make more profit!</p>
<p>Ahhhhh … now you’re talking</p>
<p>That means that you don’t tell your customers about your widget, you talk about how your widget will make their life easier/happier/quicker/more comfortable/safer.</p>
<p>If you’d like to see this copywriting technique in more detail, <a href="http://copywritematters.com/register-free-copywriting-course/">sign up for my free copywriting mini-course</a>.</p>
<h2>3. Make it personal</h2>
<p>Switching most of the instances of “We” for a “You” will immediately change the focus from the business company to the customer.</p>
<p>In fact, a good rule of thumb is to <strong>try and use the word “you” twice as much as the words “me” and “I” or “we” and “us”.</strong></p>
<p>So rather than “We provide at home consultations for your convenience” you could say “To fit in with your busy schedule, you can meet a consultant in the comfort of your living room”</p>
<p>Another way you can give your copywriting a more personal touch is write about write about your readers’ challenges and frustrations. I particularly like using the <a href="http://copywritematters.com/pas-classic-copywriting-formula/">Pain Agitate Solve (or PAS) copywriting formula</a> for this.</p>
<h2>4. Share stories and experiences from other customers</h2>
<p>Reading about someone else having the same challenges will instantly connect your customers with your solution.</p>
<p>Testimonials and case studies show some proof that real problems have been solved, for real customers. And that’s what makes a business more credible to prospective customers.</p>
<p>Powerful testimonials cover areas like:</p>
<ul>
<li>How you helped them overcome their specific problem.</li>
<li>How much profit they generated as a result.</li>
<li>How the final product met their needs.</li>
<li>Whether they were surprised by the service delivery.</li>
<li>How they found the experience with you.</li>
<li>Whether they would recommend you to their friends or colleagues.</li>
</ul>
<p>Believable testimonials also include as much detail as possible about the author of the quote (but be practical and sensitive to the amount of information people want to share about themselves).</p>
<p>Which is more believable?</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">“Business Owner, 2011”.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">or</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">“Belinda Weaver, Owner of Copywrite Matters, August 2011”</p>
<p>If you can get a photo, even better. Video testimonials blow the roof right off.</p>
<p><strong>Case studies expand on the testimonial</strong> by creating a more detailed story. A strong case study outlines:</p>
<ul>
<li>The challenge, trigger or problem that led to the connection between customer and the business.</li>
<li>The solution including the fix but also how the solution was delivered and any challenges that had to be overcome.</li>
<li>The result of everyone’s hard work. The more specific, the better!</li>
</ul>
<h2>5. Use the same language as your customers</h2>
<p>Whether you’re getting down with the young folk or pitching to a blue chip corporate audience, you can build a connection and rapport but using the same language and tone of voice as your customers.</p>
<p>When I talk about tone of voice, I’m talking about how a business expresses itself through the written word. Tone of voice covers the actual words, the order they are presented and the rhythm, pace and cadence.</p>
<p><strong>It’s what you say and how you say it.</strong></p>
<p>Kate and I dedicated an episode of our Hot Copy podcast to the <a href="http://copywritematters.com/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/hot-copy-5-copywriting-tone-voice/">tone of voice in your copywriting</a> and it’s worth a listen.</p>
<h2>Over to you</h2>
<p>What do you think? Do you have any other tips you use to connect with your customers and make it all about them?</p>
<p>Like a prison escapee, dig deep and think outside the square to connect with your reader.</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/customer-centric-copywriting-tips/">5 no-fail tricks to writing customer-centric copy (that doesn&#8217;t miss its mark)</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/customer-centric-copywriting-tips/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy podcast #30 – How to fire a client with ZERO stress</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-30-fire-copywriting-client/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-30-fire-copywriting-client/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[difficult clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[firing a client]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot copy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=8322</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;ve ever had that sinking feeling that a copywriting project just isn&#8217;t going to work out, this podcast is for you. We&#8217;ve chatted in previous podcasts about how it&#8217;s impossible to make all clients love you, and how occasionally it&#8217;s better all around if you just let them go. In this podcast we&#8217;ll be giving [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-30-fire-copywriting-client/">Hot Copy podcast #30 – How to fire a client with ZERO stress</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you&#8217;ve ever had that sinking feeling that a copywriting project just isn&#8217;t going to work out, this podcast is for you.</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5440" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>We&#8217;ve chatted in previous podcasts about how it&#8217;s impossible to make all clients love you, and how occasionally it&#8217;s better all around if you just let them go.</p>
<p>In this podcast we&#8217;ll be giving you tips and tricks on how to spot, handle and, if necessary, fire a difficult client.</p>
<h2>Tune in to learn:</h2>
<ul>
<li>How to spot bad clients</li>
<li>Tips and tricks to get difficult clients back on track</li>
<li>How to decide if firing a client is the right move</li>
<li>How to do the dirty deed of firing a client</li>
<li>Dealing with the aftermath of client firing</li>
</ul>
<p>You can also listen on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/podcast-30-fire-client-zero-stress" target="_blank">The Hot Copy podcast website</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-30-fire-copywriting-client/">Hot Copy podcast #30 – How to fire a client with ZERO stress</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-30-fire-copywriting-client/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Some surprising things you (probably) don&#8217;t know about me</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/surprising-belinda-weaver/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/surprising-belinda-weaver/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 21 Jun 2016 21:00:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Useful Tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=8235</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Hey there, I thought I&#8217;d take a break from regular programming on The Copy Detective to introduce myself a little more intimately. You may know me from a while back but if you&#8217;re new around here, Welcome! These are some things that you (probably) won&#8217;t know about me and that you might find interesting. Or not! &#160; [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/surprising-belinda-weaver/">Some surprising things you (probably) don&#8217;t know about me</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Hey there,</p>
<p>I thought I&#8217;d take a break from regular programming on <em>The Copy Detective</em> to introduce myself a little more intimately. You may know me from a while back but if you&#8217;re new around here, Welcome!</p>
<p>These are some things that you (probably) won&#8217;t know about me and that you might find interesting. Or not!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<ul>
<li>My nickname is Bill and has been since I was 14.<a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Polaroids.png"><img class="alignright wp-image-4344 size-full" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/01/Polaroids.png" alt="Belinda Weaver - copywriting courses, coaching and consulting" width="222" height="505" /></a></li>
<li>My hair is naturally red.</li>
<li>During high school, I tap danced my way to teaching qualifications. I thought it would be a good back up career.</li>
<li>I’ve never had to rely on those tap dancing qualifications [thank god].</li>
<li>I have a frustrating and uncontrollable blush response.</li>
<li>I’m always surprised when people remember who I am [which makes me blush]</li>
<li>I’m super impressed when people remember my name [which makes me blush]</li>
<li>I am quite a show pony but I don’t like being the centre of attention [it makes me blush]</li>
<li>I don’t like being caught unawares [it makes me blush]</li>
<li>I am trying to get better at remembering people’s names using key facts about them. Unfortunately that kinda makes me look stalker-ish.</li>
<li>I remember all words to the brownie-guides song I learnt when I was 10.</li>
<li>I am getting quite good at yoga. Even if I do say so myself.</li>
<li>I have never broken a bone nor do I have any allergies.</li>
<li>I used to go to Johnny Young’s Talent School and perform in Brisbane’s Queen St Mall during school holidays *jazzhands*.</li>
<li>I have two [much] older brothers although they moved out when I was little so I have the selfishness of an only child.</li>
<li>My first concert was The Village People [expo 88] and I bloody <em>loved it</em>.</li>
<li>I am obsessed with all things Japanese.</li>
<li>I have several tattoos and some of them are quite big.</li>
<li>I just started wearing a watch after about 15 years without one.</li>
<li>I used to be a cat person until I owned a dog.</li>
<li>People think I’m brave and adventurous but I think they are completely relative terms.</li>
<li>I have a BA in Information Technology and I started my career programming software at a bank.</li>
<li>I am a completely hopeless romantic. Utterly hopeless.</li>
<li>I look for something positive in every situation [my husband calls it the PollyAnna syndrome].</li>
<li>I am very tactile and gesticulate quite madly when I talk, even when you can’t see me.</li>
<li>I’m quite (very) clumsy (see above).</li>
<li>When I walk around with my headphones in I imagine that I’m in my own music video.</li>
<li>I used to consume books at an extraordinary rate (until I had a kid!) and love rereading my favourites over and over again.</li>
<li>I lived in England for four years. I loved every minute of it but I was still happy to come home to Australia.</li>
<li>I’m currently living in California although, like England, it’s not permanent.</li>
<li>I’ll usually choose savoury over sweet. Usually.</li>
<li>I think of my favourite foods in terms of the texture they have. I love crunchy things.</li>
<li>I swear. A lot. But mostly privately.</li>
<li>The more excited I get, the louder I talk [which can make the swearing all the more inappropriate]</li>
<li>I am a terrible gardener [I kill with love] but I’m working on it.</li>
<li>I could watch Doctor Who over and over again. And then again. And again.</li>
<li>I am a self-confessed dork. And proud of it.</li>
<li>I am trying to overcome my fear of spiders so I don’t pass that fear onto my mini-Weaver. Thankfully, California does not have the spider population that Australia does.</li>
<li>I am definitely a gin and tonic girl. And a beer girl. I also love a nice mojito. [I’ll stop there before I look like an alchie].</li>
<li>I am very loyal to the people I love and I love people easily.</li>
<li>I tap my keyboard <em>really</em> hard and I don’t really know why. It’s clearly not necessary.</li>
<li>I am really proud of the work I do.</li>
<li>I just can’t seem to tick along at medium pace. I’m always putting more on my plate to see if I can do it.</li>
</ul>
<p>Are we friends now?</p>
<p>I&#8217;d love to know some surprising things about you. Let&#8217;s get comfy and share!</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em> &#8212; Belinda</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/surprising-belinda-weaver/">Some surprising things you (probably) don&#8217;t know about me</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/surprising-belinda-weaver/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>8</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy podcast #29 – What to do when your copywriting client goes A.W.O.L.</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-29-copywriting-clients-awol/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-29-copywriting-clients-awol/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Jun 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Useful Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[advice]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot copy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=8063</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Once you’ve got a few copywriting projects under your belt, you learn that some clients will respond very quickly and others will take a short ice age to reply. But how long is too long? When do you know your client is MISSING IN ACTION and what should you do? Tune in to learn: Why [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-29-copywriting-clients-awol/">Hot Copy podcast #29 – What to do when your copywriting client goes A.W.O.L.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5440" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Once you’ve got a few copywriting projects under your belt, you learn that some clients will respond very quickly and others will take a short ice age to reply. But how long is too long? When do you know your client is MISSING IN ACTION and what should you do?</p>
<h2>Tune in to learn:</h2>
<ul>
<li>Why clients legitimately go missing</li>
<li>How long should you wait?</li>
<li>How too long is too long?</li>
<li>How you can avoid having clients go missing</li>
<li>How to follow up with clients after the quote, proposal, first draft and last draft</li>
<li>What to do if the worst happens.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Listen on:</h2>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/podcast-29-copywriting-client-goes-awol" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/podcast-26-interview-with-copywriter-amy-harrison">The Hot Copy podcast website</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And thanks to Mac Prichard for the fab review we read out on the show!</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-29-copywriting-clients-awol/">Hot Copy podcast #29 – What to do when your copywriting client goes A.W.O.L.</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-29-copywriting-clients-awol/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Copywriting not using this word? You’re missing some serious persuasion power</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-persuasive-power/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-persuasive-power/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriter]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[persuasion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=8116</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>My two-year-old is upping her game on persuasion, and she recently hit upon one of the most persuasive words a copywriter can use to encourage action. Because. Now, coming from my two-year-old, persuasion sounds something like this: I want another cracker because I want another cracker. Or I want to watch TV because I want [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-persuasive-power/">Copywriting not using this word? You’re missing some serious persuasion power</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Becauseblogpost.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-8125 " src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/Becauseblogpost.jpg" alt="Blog about powering up your copywriting" width="658" height="370" /></a></p>
<p>My two-year-old is upping her game on persuasion, and she recently hit upon one of the most persuasive words a copywriter can use to encourage action.</p>
<p>Because.</p>
<p>Now, coming from my two-year-old, persuasion sounds something like this:</p>
<p>I want another cracker because I want another cracker.<br />
Or<br />
I want to watch TV because I want to watch TV.</p>
<p>Not very subtle, right? But studies have shown that the reason given actually doesn’t matter as much as the act of giving a reason.</p>
<h2>Let me explain.</h2>
<p>In the late 1970s, psychologists Langer, Chanowitz and Blank (of the Graduate Center, The City University of New York) ran <a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/06/copy-machine-study-ellen-langer.pdf" target="_blank">a language experiment</a>. It centred on a humble photocopier. Simply put, participants in the experiment interrupted someone about to start photocopying, asking to cut in the queue. The results measured how effective different ways of asking were.</p>
<p>There were three approaches:</p>
<ol>
<li><strong>Request only.</strong> &#8220;Excuse me, I have 5 (or 20) pages. May I use the Xerox machine?&#8221;</li>
<li><strong>Placebic information.</strong> &#8220;Excuse me, I have 5 (or 20) pages. May I use the Xerox machine because I have to make copies?&#8221;</li>
<li><strong>Real information.</strong> &#8220;Excuse me, I have 5 (or 20) pages. May I use the Xerox machine because I&#8217;m in a rush?&#8221;</li>
</ol>
<p>When the participants asked to cut in the queue without giving a reason, 60% were allowed to do so. When they explained why they wanted to cut in line, the conversion rate shot up to over 90%.</p>
<p>A quote from the study explains, “If a reason was presented to the subject, <strong>he or she was more likely to comply than if no reason was presented</strong>, <em>even if the reason conveyed no information.</em> Once compliance with the request required a modicum of effort on the subject&#8217;s part, thoughtful responding seemed to take the place of mindlessness, and the reason now seemed to matter. Under these circumstances, subjects were more likely to comply with the request based on the adequacy of the reason presented.”</p>
<p>So a mindless reason only works when the action requires limited effort, such as letting someone make 5 copies but not 20 (which is why Miss 2 often gets another cracker). But when the effort is great, <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/iamcopywritematters/you-tube-benefits-vs-features" target="_blank">the reason has to be great too</a>.</p>
<h3>In either case, the linking word “because” is a persuasion-bomb.</h3>
<p>Let’s look at some examples that go beyond the world of a two-year-old.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Order now <em>because</em> we offer same-day shipping on orders before 2pm!</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Come and see us in-store <em>because</em> we’re giving away FREE signed copies of the Sanity Saving Guide to Raising Exceptional Toddlers, while stocks last.</p>
<p>And not just for inciting some action. You can use this technique to reinforce the importance of your statement.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><a href="http://copywritematters.com/no-fail-tricks-for-customer-centric-copy/" target="_blank">These copywriting techniques</a> are essential because they remind you to focus on your reader.</p>
<h2>But wait; there’s more!</h2>
<p>You can also use explanations to offset negatives by explaining why something doesn&#8217;t happen.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Orders cannot be cancelled.<br />
vs.<br />
Orders cannot be cancelled <em>because</em> we use express same-day shipping…and they&#8217;ve already been sent!</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">A 25% surcharge is added for urgent projects.<br />
vs.<br />
A 25% surcharge is added for urgent projects <em>because</em> we have to bump other projects to complete yours. And that means overtime.</p>
<h2>Ahhhh the power of because!</h2>
<p>Hopefully you can see how much this word can achieve in your copywriting.</p>
<p>If you find yourself needing to persuade your reader—and as copywriters, that’s our brief—give them a reason to say yes!</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>This is just one of the many persuasive writing techniques I cover in my <a href="http://copywritematters.com/learn-copywriting-course/" target="_blank">Copywriting Master Class copywriting course</a>. If you’d like to find out more and be part of the next exclusively small group of students, <a href="http://copywritematters.com/learn-copywriting-course/" target="_blank">check it out here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-persuasive-power/">Copywriting not using this word? You’re missing some serious persuasion power</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-persuasive-power/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy podcast #28 – New copywriter&#8217;s guide to blogging</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-28-new-copywriters-guide-to-blogging/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-28-new-copywriters-guide-to-blogging/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Useful Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blogging tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ideas]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=8067</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Blogging certainly isn’t new but it is a source of anxiety for many new copywriters, especially when it feels like it’s all been done before. In this episode, Kate and Belinda break down the walls of blogging, sharing their views on the importance of blogging and how to get your blog working hard for your [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-28-new-copywriters-guide-to-blogging/">Hot Copy podcast #28 – New copywriter&#8217;s guide to blogging</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5440" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Blogging certainly isn’t new but it is a source of anxiety for many new copywriters, especially when it feels like it’s all been done before. In this episode, Kate and Belinda break down the walls of blogging, sharing their views on the importance of blogging and how to get your blog working hard for your business.</p>
<h2>Tune in to learn:</h2>
<ul>
<li>If you actually need to blog</li>
<li>How to write authority</li>
<li>If copywriting is all you can and should write about</li>
<li>Why Kate says vagina multiple times</li>
<li>How often you should blog</li>
<li>How long your blogs need to be</li>
<li>Tips on writing about well covered topics</li>
<li>Where to get blog ideas</li>
<li>Guest posting, on your blog and others</li>
<li>How to get your blogs noticed</li>
</ul>
<h2>Listen on:</h2>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/podcast-28-blog-youre-just-starting" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/podcast-26-interview-with-copywriter-amy-harrison">The Hot Copy podcast website</a></li>
</ul>
<p>And thanks to Melissa East for her 5 star review!</p>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-28-new-copywriters-guide-to-blogging/">Hot Copy podcast #28 – New copywriter&#8217;s guide to blogging</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-28-new-copywriters-guide-to-blogging/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Want copywriting x-ray vision? 3 lenses to reveal audience motives</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 24 May 2016 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=7975</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Understanding your reader and what motivates them is the key to effective copywriting. When you can mirror readers’ thoughts and feelings, you show them that you understand them, and that generates feelings of trust and credibility. And when someone trusts you their barriers to your persuasion are way down. But understanding your audience can be hard. [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/">Want copywriting x-ray vision? 3 lenses to reveal audience motives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Motivesbloggraphic.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-7982 " src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/Motivesbloggraphic.jpg" alt="Copywriting motives graphic" width="510" height="604" /></a></p>
<p>Understanding your reader and what motivates them is the key to effective copywriting.</p>
<p>When you can mirror readers’ thoughts and feelings, you show them that you <em>understand</em> them, and that generates feelings of trust and credibility. And when someone trusts you <strong>their barriers to your persuasion are way down.</strong></p>
<p>But understanding your audience can be hard. I mean, if they&#8217;re just like you, it&#8217;s easy but more often than not you&#8217;re writing copy to persuade an audience that&#8217;s entirely <em>unlike</em> you.</p>
<p>So how do you go about the task of understanding the why behind their actions?</p>
<p>This post covers three different lenses that can give you x-ray vision about your audiences&#8217; motives.</p>
<h2>Let&#8217;s begin with Bob Bly</h2>
<p>Copywriter Bob Bly (All Hail) has a fantastic list of motivators. He explains that people buy something:</p>
<table width="907">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="464">
<ul>
<li><strong>To be liked</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be appreciated</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be right</strong></li>
<li><strong>To feel important</strong></li>
<li><strong>To make money</strong></li>
<li><strong>To save money</strong></li>
<li><strong>To save time</strong></li>
<li><strong>To make work easier</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be secure</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be attractive</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be sexy</strong></li>
</ul>
</td>
<td width="464">
<ul>
<li><strong>To be comfortable</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be distinctive</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be happy</strong></li>
<li><strong>To have fun</strong></li>
<li><strong>To gain knowledge</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be healthy</strong></li>
<li><strong>To gratify curiosity</strong></li>
<li><strong>For convenience</strong></li>
<li><strong>Out of fear</strong></li>
<li><strong>Out of greed</strong></li>
<li><strong>Out of guilt</strong></li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>It’s a great list isn’t it?</p>
<p>I really like the simplicity of these motives. We can all identify with them and they give us lots of different angles to work with.</p>
<h2>Let&#8217;s dig deeper into marketing theory</h2>
<p>In marketing theory, all those motives can be broken down to the five basic priorities that drive our decisions.</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/MaslowsHeirarchyofNeeds.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-7976 " src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/MaslowsHeirarchyofNeeds.jpg" alt="Maslows Heirarchy of Needs" width="742" height="462" /></a></p>
<h4>This is a classic marketing diagram known as Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs.</h4>
<ol>
<li>First we look after our physiological needs. We make sure we have shelter, food, water and warmth so <strong>we can survive.</strong></li>
<li>Once they are taken care of, we look to <strong>make sure we are safe.</strong> Safety could be lock and key protection or something more high-level like contractual safety.</li>
<li>When we can survive and we’re safe, we look to fill our <strong>need for social interaction</strong> and love. <strong>Following that, our self-esteem.</strong></li>
<li>Finally, when we have what we need to survive, we’re safe, we have a sense of belonging and our self-esteem is being taken care of… then we <strong>look to achieve our potential as humans.</strong></li>
</ol>
<h2>Let&#8217;s end with some research</h2>
<p>The last model I want to share with you was created by Ernest Dichter, known as “the father of motivational research”.</p>
<p>He mapped out 12 motives that drive our desires, fears and our shopping:</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Power/Masculinity/Virility</strong></td>
<td width="539">Strength and dominance!</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Security</strong></td>
<td width="539">Safety as well as home comfort</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Eroticism </strong></td>
<td width="539">Sexuality and desire. Sex sells!</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Cleanliness/Moral Purity</strong></td>
<td width="539">Cleanliness isn’t just functional, moral purity is often implied in the colours and imagery used</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Social Acceptance</strong></td>
<td width="539">Companionship, approval and love</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Individuality</strong></td>
<td width="539">The desire to be unique</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Status</strong></td>
<td width="539">Feeling important, respected and successful</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Femininity</strong></td>
<td width="539">All things associated with being feminine</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Reward</strong></td>
<td width="539">Maximising our payoff</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Mastery over environment</strong></td>
<td width="539">Competence and mastery. Can be closely related to <em>reward</em> and <em>power</em>.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Disalienation </strong></td>
<td width="539">The desire to feel connectedness to things. <em>This is often seen in fast food outlets. The food can be a little different around the world but there is a sameness that we crave.</em></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Magic and mystery</strong></td>
<td width="539">Powers unseen, surprises and moods</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<h2>3 lenses = deeper understanding</h2>
<p><strong>The lesson: when you understand what <em>really</em> motivates someone to act, you can override their rational brain. </strong></p>
<p>That&#8217;s the one telling them NOT to buy. Instead, you talk to the little voice that’s <em>really</em> running the show.</p>
<p>Together, these models give you different lenses to see your reader through, which means lots of different ways to consider their motives.</p>
<h2>Your task</h2>
<p>Before you sit down to write a headline, call to action or an entire website of copy, take some time to consider what is <em>really</em> motivating your audience (beyond the obvious rational motives).</p>
<p><strong>And dig deep.</strong> Because the motives that live deeply within in us usually have the most power.</p>
<p>When you understand them, you can choose <a href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriter-words-that-sell/" target="_blank">copywriting language</a> that cuts straight to the heart of the matter.</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p><em>This post has been an excerpt from my <a href="http://copywritematters.com/learn-copywriting-course/" target="_blank">Copywriting Master Class copywriting course</a>. If you&#8217;d like to find out more and be part of the next exclusively small group of students, <a href="http://copywritematters.com/learn-copywriting-course/" target="_blank">check it out here</a>.</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/">Want copywriting x-ray vision? 3 lenses to reveal audience motives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
