<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Copywrite Matters</title>
	<atom:link href="http://copywritematters.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://copywritematters.com</link>
	<description>Copywriting courses, coaching, content</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 04:19:07 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.8.6</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Why you need a little About Me on your website</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/about-me-page/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/about-me-page/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Useful Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[About me page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[blog pages]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[website pages]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.copywritematters.com.au/?p=939</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Okay. Obviously, I don’t mean that you need a little about ME on your website (although that would be nice wouldn’t it?). When I say About Me, I mean about YOU and I’m referring the About page on your website. I know many copywriting clients and copywriters would prefer to skip this critical page altogether citing, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/about-me-page/">Why you need a little About Me on your website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Okay. Obviously, I don’t mean that you need a little about ME on your website (although that would be nice wouldn’t it?).</p>
<p>When I say About Me, I mean about YOU and I’m referring<strong> the About page on your website. </strong></p>
<p>I know many copywriting clients and copywriters would prefer to skip this critical page altogether citing, “oh, no one will be interested in <em>me</em>” and they couldn’t be more wrong.</p>
<p><strong>The About page is possibly one of the most important pages on your website</strong> after the homepage and that’s not just because it’s usually the most visited, which it is.</p>
<p>The first step in planning the content for your website’s About page is understanding why people visit the page in the first place. Your potential clients simply want to know:</p>
<h2><strong>Who you are</strong></h2>
<p>Your About page gives you a chance to tell your story and <strong>it’s your story that will give your reader the opportunity to develop a connection with you.</strong></p>
<p>That connection could be the difference between getting in touch or closing that website forever.</p>
<p>Don’t be afraid to put a name and a face to your business and remind the person reading right now that you are, in fact, a human being. People buy from people and the point of clicking on to an About page is to find a human connection.</p>
<p>You probably don&#8217;t want to share information about what&#8217;s in your bathroom cabinet or the names and ages of your kids but it can be really useful to share the details of:</p>
<ul>
<li><em>how</em> and <em>why</em> you got started</li>
<li><em>why</em> you keep doing what you do (what you love about it)</li>
<li>some personal snippets, like your favourite movie or jam.</li>
</ul>
<p>This kind of information helps a potential client understand what you might be like to work with. And working with a copywriter can be an intense collaboration&#8230; liking each other, even a little, can really help.</p>
<h2><strong>That <em>you </em>know what you’re talking about</strong></h2>
<p>Life tells us that liking someone will only get a relationship so far. There has to be more. Like actual expertise. So, apart from sharing that you love <em>Thirteenth Warrior</em> with Antonio Banderas, help potential clients feel confident that you know your stuff by including information about your expertise.</p>
<ul>
<li>what did you do before writing copy?</li>
<li>how does that background serve your clients?</li>
<li>what do you specialise in now?</li>
</ul>
<h2><strong>That you understand where <em>they </em>are coming from</strong></h2>
<p>Remember that clients are only interested in how your experience will benefit them. While you need to include enough details about your expertise make you credible, your About page shouldn’t be a chronological story of your life.</p>
<p>So, rather than talking about yourself, talk about your reader. <strong>Link your experience to their outcome using phrases such as:</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">What that means for you is&#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">That means I can write copy that&#8230;</p>
<h2><strong>What to do next</strong></h2>
<p>Every piece of marketing needs a call to action. Especially your about page!</p>
<p>You&#8217;ve just spent the page making a connection with a potential client. They get a sense of who you are as a person and what you might be like to work with and they feel confident in your ability to get the job done.</p>
<p>Ahhhh, warm and fuzzies all around!</p>
<p>Don&#8217;t let the moment pass without giving them some guidance on what to do next. Read your latest blog post, or get a quote, or download your super duper report. Whatever it is, make sure you end your page with an action.</p>
<p>So go and take a look at your About page now. Have you checked those points off? Do you think there is room for improvement or perhaps you disagree? Let me know!</p>
<p><em>Belinda (AKA The Copy Detective)</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/about-me-page/">Why you need a little About Me on your website</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/about-me-page/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>5</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Warning: Your oh so clever copywriting could be unreadable</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/warning-clever-copywriting/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/warning-clever-copywriting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 11 Jun 2018 21:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Useful Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[readability]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9696</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Always choose clarity over cleverness. It&#8217;s a copywriter&#8217;s mantra but many writers can&#8217;t wait to pop on their clever trousers, assuming that the more clever their copywriting is the more professional it is. And the result is, well, it&#8217;s unreadable. It&#8217;s not that cleverness has no place in copywriting. Not at all. It&#8217;s just that the [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/warning-clever-copywriting/">Warning: Your oh so clever copywriting could be unreadable</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<h4><strong>Always choose clarity over cleverness.</strong></h4>
<p>It&#8217;s a copywriter&#8217;s mantra but many writers can&#8217;t wait to pop on their clever trousers, assuming that the more clever their copywriting is the more professional it is.</p>
<p>And the result is, well, it&#8217;s unreadable.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s not that cleverness has no place in copywriting. Not at all. It&#8217;s just that the easier your messages are to read, the easier they are understood <em>and actioned</em>!</p>
<h4>Copywriting 101 says: Make sure your message is aimed at the right audience, matching their education and vocabulary.</h4>
<p>As a copywriter, you&#8217;re not writing for you. You&#8217;re not even writing for your client. You are writing for <em>their customers</em>.</p>
<p>And a general rule of thumb, unless your target market has specific language needs (like being under 5, or super clever university boffins) <strong>marketing copywriting should be aimed at a high school education level</strong> – Year 9 or 10.</p>
<p><em>How can you tell?</em></p>
<p id="afbcda1c-2e9b-4199-8bcb-4e54785d4b8f">Tools like this <a href="http://www.readability-score.com/" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.readability-score.com/">online tool for text readability</a> are also really useful. You simply plug in some text and get a grade rating. You’ll see there are a few different formulas and it’s quite interesting to see the results.</p>
<p id="3c23923a-ec6a-43a5-9a6c-b0e7fbab9f73"><strong>Remember: the higher the grade needed to read your copywriting, the harder it is for a wider audience to understand. </strong>And lowering the grade doesn’t mean talking down to your audience. Just taking the hot air out of your copywriting.</p>
<h3>How can you improve the readability of your copywriting?</h3>
<p>If your want your copy to be understood without distractions, <strong>exchange long words for shorter (less ambiguous) words</strong> and <strong>reduce the average length of your sentences.</strong></p>
<p>Here’s a great guide on readability vs sentence length:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Very easy             8 words or fewer<br />
Easy                      9 – 11 words<br />
Fairly easy          12 – 14  words<br />
Standard             15 – 17  words<br />
Fairly difficult    18 – 21  words<br />
Difficult               22 – 25  words<br />
Very difficult      26 – 30  words</p>
<p>Remember: The longer the sentences and the more complicated the language, the harder your copywriting is to understand.</p>
<p><strong>And it&#8217;s not just the words you need to simplify.</strong></p>
<p>Simplifying your ideas is also key. And again, because it&#8217;s important, <strong>simplifying isn&#8217;t dumbing down.</strong> It&#8217;s ditching all the fluff and hot air to focus on <em>the core issues, pains and solutions.    </em></p>
<h3>Another great tool to boost readability</h3>
<p>If you haven&#8217;t heard of the <a href="http://www.hemingwayapp.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hemingway App</a>, where have you been? It&#8217;s a fantastic (and free) tool that critiques your copywriting.</p>
<p>The tips it automatically gives you include:</p>
<blockquote><p>The app highlights lengthy, complex sentences and common errors; if you see a yellow sentence, shorten or split it. If you see a red highlight, your sentence is so dense and complicated that your readers will get lost trying to follow its meandering, splitting logic — try editing this sentence to remove the red.</p>
<p>You can utilize a shorter word in place of a purple one. Mouse over them for hints.</p>
<p>Adverbs and weakening phrases are shown in blue. Get rid of them and pick words with force, perhaps&gt;Phrases in green have <span class="passivevoice"><span data-offset-key="e9j1-1-0"><span data-text="true">been marked to show passive voice.</span></span></span></p></blockquote>
<p>You may not implement every single suggestion but it&#8217;s a great tool to use in your editing phase.</p>
<p>As I&#8217;ve become more experienced as a copywriter, it&#8217;s the editing phase that takes more of my time and effort. So a tool or two is always welcome!</p>
<p>What about you? How do you improve the readability of your copy?</p>
<p><em>Belinda</em></p>
<p>This post scores 9.3 on the <a href="https://readable.io/content/the-flesch-reading-ease-and-flesch-kincaid-grade-level/" data-cke-saved-href="https://readable.io/content/the-flesch-reading-ease-and-flesch-kincaid-grade-level/">Flesch-Kincaid Grade Level</a> although it did try and tell me a few of my words had too many syllables. This is where you have to use your own judgement as well. I don&#8217;t think vocabulary is too much for you&#8230; is it?</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/warning-clever-copywriting/">Warning: Your oh so clever copywriting could be unreadable</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/warning-clever-copywriting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>20</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How 10-dollar words make your copywriting suck</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/why-10-dollar-words-make-your-copywriting-suck/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/why-10-dollar-words-make-your-copywriting-suck/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Useful Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[10 dollar words]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting clarity]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.copywritematters.com.au/?p=1336</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>10 dollar words are the fancy words that you think make you look smart. You hope that by including a longer, more complicated word than you need, readers will go: “Oooh, sounds like she really knows her stuff!” In reality, 10-dollar words make your copywriting suck. I’m not suggesting that you should never use more than [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/why-10-dollar-words-make-your-copywriting-suck/">How 10-dollar words make your copywriting suck</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="70dfd586-83f2-4435-a905-e4c5acf9746f">10 dollar words are the fancy words that you think make you look smart. You hope that by including a longer, more complicated word than you need, readers will go: “Oooh, sounds like she really knows her stuff!”</p>
<p id="fcc00b76-8d6c-4796-ba04-fffc9220570e">In reality, <strong>10-dollar words make your copywriting suck.</strong></p>
<p id="640d2882-cc16-404d-9bc4-37d94cca5b90">I’m not suggesting that you should never use more than three syllables to communicate a concept. English is full of wonderful words that are a pleasure to say and see but if your reader has to spend even one extra second to translate your copy, you’ve lost the rhythm and you might just lose the reader.</p>
<h2><strong>Don’t spend 10-dollars on a 2 dollar job</strong></h2>
<p id="b7ece957-34e4-46dc-b961-9a7a321b00ba">Cutting out 10-dollar words from your copywriting doesn’t mean you have to dumb everything down but 10-dollar words are <em><strong>unnecessarily </strong>complicated</em>.</p>
<p id="fcea9933-c24a-4c5a-aff7-fda6f8a49c36">If you botch up the execution you risk sounding pretentious. Unless that’s the tone you’re going for, communicate using simpler but more meaningful language.</p>
<h2><strong>Turn inflated into straightforward</strong></h2>
<p id="e3c80714-cce3-4bb5-87ee-4c6f4f4d95d8">Do you need to say <em>cease </em>when you could say <em>stop</em>? Or <em>transportation </em>when you mean <em>lorries</em>?</p>
<p id="26f61279-6354-4b93-a874-a024956c1bcb">You might think you’re adding sparkle to your copywriting but, really, you’re just filling it with hot air.</p>
<p id="66c3c0ed-7575-49c4-b3cc-a8f398e18751">Here are some of my favourite* 10-dollar words and the words I think they should be replaced with. *<em>When I say favourite, I mean the ones that make me roll my eyes and sigh dramatically.</em></p>
<p id="416e6dee-3c1b-4970-8855-06d3401a3914" style="padding-left: 30px;">    Disintermediation = cutting out the middleman</p>
<p id="b35659cf-cab7-4d88-8fbc-5366dd230494" style="padding-left: 30px;">    Heuristic = Formula or guide</p>
<p id="5fa38267-13cb-4e8a-bf40-b7f04be9443d" style="padding-left: 30px;">    Exacerbate = Aggravate/make worse</p>
<p id="53120c5f-a02c-4ddc-a922-567e8fc39bf7" style="padding-left: 30px;">    Agrestic = Rustic or handmade</p>
<p id="0f807b4c-b599-4e4d-9816-ab64c39e9567" style="padding-left: 30px;">    Reintegration = Integration</p>
<p id="116de78e-fc24-4e4c-be2f-26fe426860d9" style="padding-left: 30px;">    Nomenclature = Language</p>
<p id="35fe7940-8d0a-489b-877f-ae231863721d">My old boss would use nomenclature all. the. time&#8230; I love the word but he&#8217;d always look so damned pleased with himself! It was nauseating.</p>
<p id="803b5419-21cc-4000-8632-3ba41c3f2d21">Some more common ones you will see (and use are):</p>
<p id="1386fd7d-4651-47e4-96c8-83d17ce9d51c" style="padding-left: 30px;">     Commence = Start</p>
<p id="fe11f9ea-9ea6-4244-810e-a1e1b838cbd7" style="padding-left: 30px;">     Terminate = End</p>
<p id="99f5ac26-5982-4195-b377-864b3e82ad2b" style="padding-left: 30px;">     Facilitate = Help</p>
<p id="5ba78f01-68d4-4502-828c-745a4188c202" style="padding-left: 30px;">     Utilise = Use</p>
<p id="b257535f-018c-431a-932a-84645be24e82" style="padding-left: 30px;">     In the event of = If</p>
<p id="0a935e67-197d-4ac3-b769-037c2623ccca" style="padding-left: 30px;">     Prior to = Before</p>
<p id="865082d9-1819-491b-99ff-d1e1acca4b2b" style="padding-left: 30px;">     At this point in time = Now</p>
<p id="3b5a99a9-2d0d-48e0-9484-4d40f56c4dba" style="padding-left: 30px;">     In excess of = More than</p>
<p id="bc3a2949-6eb1-43bc-9d4d-f1a5bbf939ff" style="padding-left: 30px;">     Purchase = Buy</p>
<p id="b5f6db88-d363-4cdf-88fb-76a585d0c50e" style="padding-left: 30px;">     Receive = Get</p>
<p id="32e8f344-6c4a-481a-96fa-50c48ca91713">It almost every case, the more complicated version just isn&#8217;t needed.</p>
<p id="4bcfabcb-e04c-48fe-886c-683f9a305733">One way to find these words? Read your copy aloud. They&#8217;ve got nowhere to run when you do that because they usually sound out of place. Or you sound pompous.</p>
<p><strong>You may as well say “Wiffle Blah Pokem”</strong></p>
<p>Overused words can be just as detrimental to your copywriting.</p>
<p id="874d23db-03b1-476e-afad-40909b36c236">When you roll out some of those overused words and phrases, they can lack their intended meaning and add nothing to your copywriting. Some examples:</p>
<p id="50e56192-c4f3-42a8-84d0-e34018809cfc" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>     Authority, Characteristic, Commitment, Information, Intrinsic, Innovative, Operational, Procedure, </em></p>
<p id="88727c00-6c42-46a3-9fab-e4b4e5b894d8" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>     Provider, Relationship, Standards, Strategy, Scalable solution, Solution, System</em></p>
<p id="5474c940-230a-4e36-b37c-5e29e36f3bd8">Sometimes some of these are used in combination for extra points on ‘Management Speak Bingo’.</p>
<p id="360b971e-c548-4f96-892d-01327f0b89b8" style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>     Do you leverage best practise, think outside the box or tap into a core competency? </em></p>
<p id="2bfae431-6c8e-4b15-a550-3a60a93971a4">(Furious eye stabbing.)</p>
<p id="b13009db-3823-45f8-a34a-8d2c0b909a21"><strong>They fill the space but they don’t add anything concrete to your copywriting.</strong> You may as well say “Wiffle Blah Pokem”.</p>
<p id="7e9620e3-f175-4655-a596-09a18616cc2a">The challenge is that these words have become so ingrained that it&#8217;s harder to convince someone (a client) that they are B.S. Sometimes it&#8217;s even difficult for us to see a simpler version.</p>
<p id="60fc5596-02f8-4bd2-93e4-4eebed309ba8">Your job is to turn these abstract phrases and concepts into tangible ideas using REAL WORDS.</p>
<p><br data-cke-eol="1" />So now it’s over to you. Which 10-dollar words do you hate seeing? Which ones are actually ok to use? I’d love to get your thoughts…</p>
<p><em>Belinda (AKA The Copy Detective)</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/why-10-dollar-words-make-your-copywriting-suck/">How 10-dollar words make your copywriting suck</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/why-10-dollar-words-make-your-copywriting-suck/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>When to use jargon: A copywriter’s guide</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-jargon/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-jargon/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Jun 2018 21:00:57 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Useful Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[acronyms]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jargon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[technical terms]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=5671</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>One of the big rules of copywriting is to ditch complicated language. When you use simpler words, your copywriting becomes more readable and that increases your chances of it being effective. It makes sense, doesn’t it? While this is a great rule most of the time, there are some exceptions. There are moments when jargon [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-jargon/">When to use jargon: A copywriter’s guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>One of the big rules of copywriting is to <a title="Why Those 10-dollar Words Make Your Copywriting Suck" href="http://copywritematters.com/why-10-dollar-words-make-your-copywriting-suck/">ditch complicated language</a>. When you use simpler words, <a title="Readable = Understandable. Don’t let your copywriting get too clever." href="http://copywritematters.com/readable-understandable-copywriting-clever/">your copywriting becomes more readable</a> and that increases your chances of it being effective.</p>
<p>It makes sense, doesn’t it?</p>
<p>While this is a great rule <em>most of the time, </em>there are some exceptions.</p>
<p>There are moments when jargon will actually enhance your copywriting. Say, Whaaaaat?</p>
<p>Let me explain.</p>
<h2>The Oxford Dictionary defines jargon as:</h2>
<p id="cac918e8-24f2-4457-9d1f-c891dd62c9f1"><em>Noun [mass noun]</em> special words or expressions used by a profession or group that are difficult for others to understand.</p>
<p id="233c0885-25cd-4976-8c9c-572180e3bc39">Some of the reasons you may want to stop making things easy for people are:</p>
<h2>You are writing to <em>exclude </em>people</h2>
<p>That&#8217;s right. Did you know that <a href="http://copywritematters.com/geishas-taught-exclusion-copywriting/">Geishas have a secret language</a>? You need to know it (as well a jump a lot of other hurdles) if you want to meet with one.</p>
<p id="be7af01e-cb97-4c46-9636-fa02255ee030">As a copywriter, creating barriers to our message is usually the exact opposite of what we want to achieve but jargon can help you gain some currency with an in-crowd.</p>
<p id="c939d10d-4a4f-4be9-865e-7eaa8e5a4046">Readers can feel smug knowing they have clever trousers on and they <em>get it</em>, unlike other readers.</p>
<p id="c7d248f4-1d3f-4efb-ab5a-1e11ed6691fd">The language might be slang or highbrow language but (when used with caution) it can <strong>help you narrow the field of your audience and create some exclusivity</strong>.</p>
<h2>You want to create a sense of enhanced value</h2>
<p id="be6782f2-9096-4b76-8f34-d612810a6761">Value is in the mind of the beholder and you can make the ordinary seem extraordinary with a little bit of wordplay.</p>
<p id="bf66e198-a791-450d-8d54-4804ded28395">Seriously, which would you prefer?</p>
<p id="22d0b126-ed0d-4cca-80ef-294b0dcfc582" style="padding-left: 60px;">A certified, pre-owned car or a used car?</p>
<p id="8b6455aa-0083-40bc-bbbd-1563e43cfc85" style="padding-left: 60px;">A grande latte or a medium coffee?</p>
<p id="5f67f6b1-45a1-4854-9ca9-0ed72f333052" style="padding-left: 60px;">To learn to write a lede or an introduction?</p>
<p id="29c70e8e-373d-4fc7-986f-50b041784532">You need to be careful that you aren’t inflating your copy just for the hell of it (or because a client thinks it makes them sound important) because then you’re just writing fluff <strong>and all the other copywriters will laugh at you.</strong></p>
<h2>You are writing about a technical topic</h2>
<p id="0c3c81c2-5b17-43ee-929e-6492eb688f20">There are lots of industries that have their own language – everything from IT and engineering to blogging and craft. The more specialised the topic, the more specialised the language.</p>
<p id="c6ec6c53-b534-4f01-95a2-ae6bce7a99d1">If your copywriting is selling a technical product to a technical audience, you must speak the same language.</p>
<p id="96a58707-6fff-4fa9-95c5-1dca7a3dff45">This is when jargon gets some credibility and becomes <em>terminology</em>. Terminology helps you describe something precisely and, more often than not, simpler substitutes just don’t exist.</p>
<h2>What about acronyms?</h2>
<p>I don’t know about you but there seem to be so many more acronyms around these days. I have to Google most chat and text acronyms. There, I&#8217;ve said it. I&#8217;m not down with the kids, at all.</p>
<p>If you’re going to use an acronym, explain the term in full with the acronym following in parentheses. You only have to explain it once but make sure you’re consistent in how you present it.</p>
<p>The same with abbreviations.</p>
<p>For example, don’t switch between explaining business-to-business as B2B then B-to-B.</p>
<h2 id="1f062b55-2bce-4d0f-8ab0-bbad25dea9f2">Bob Bly, copywriter, says:</h2>
<p id="ae56fb10-e463-4e23-aae9-846730512a16"><em>“Even when using legitimate technical terms and acronyms, don&#8217;t overdo it. A sentence packed with too many acronyms and technical terms seems cold, inhuman, and almost unreadable. The optimal ratio is no more than one technical term for every ten words in the sentence.”</em></p>
<p id="d18995e9-9fd0-4fdd-aa7d-437c047ca680">I don’t know about you but seeming cold and inhuman is never one of my copywriting goals!</p>
<p>If you’re wondering if it’s acceptable to use jargon in your copywriting then your decision should come back to three golden rules of copywriting:</p>
<ol>
<li>Know your audience.</li>
<li>Know your audience.</li>
<li>Know your audience.</li>
</ol>
<h2>When in doubt, leave the jargon out or explain it!</h2>
<p>Are you a secret jargon junkie? Go on – you can tell me. We’re all friends here. Or perhaps you know of other circumstances in which jargon is perfectly acceptable?</p>
<p><em>Belinda </em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-jargon/">When to use jargon: A copywriter’s guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-jargon/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>13</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Geishas and the secret power of exclusion in copywriting</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/geishas-taught-exclusion-copywriting/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/geishas-taught-exclusion-copywriting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Useful Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exclusive language]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.copywritematters.com.au/?p=437</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I love all things Japanese. You might call me a Japanophile. I have kimonos, art, books, statues, tattoos. Oh, the list goes on. I recently reread one of my favourite books, Geisha: The secret history of a vanishing world, by Lesley Downer. It&#8217;s said that the author delved further into the ‘flower and willow world’ [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/geishas-taught-exclusion-copywriting/">Geishas and the secret power of exclusion in copywriting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I love all things Japanese. You might call me a Japanophile. I have kimonos, art, books, statues, tattoos. Oh, the list goes on.</p>
<p>I recently reread one of my favourite books, <em>Geisha: The secret history of a vanishing world</em>, by Lesley Downer. It&#8217;s said that the author delved further into the ‘flower and willow world’ than any other outsider.</p>
<p>To spend time the world of the geisha you need money, the correct introductions, and you need to know the lingo. It struck me, as I read, that this secret language and barriers to connection make the geisha more exclusive.</p>
<p><strong>The language you use in your copywriting can have exactly this effect</strong>, drawing an invisible boundary that only some people can cross.</p>
<p>While jargon and in-jokes and fancy, formal dialogue are generally shunned for copywriting with broad appeal, you can <strong>use them to your advantage and create your own “members only” club for your message.</strong></p>
<p>If you are writing for a distinct group of people &#8211; <em>know their language</em>. And use it.</p>
<h3 id="9f544052-63eb-4da5-900f-90ec72eca9e5">It doesn&#8217;t work for&#8230;</h3>
<p id="cce913e5-2175-4c37-977d-7e44660c9b32"><strong>It doesn&#8217;t work for businesses that are complicated and that complication is a barrier to customers.</strong> Like, asbestos removal or law firms. These businesses need to have that complication and jargon removed so that customers feel easy about saying yes (because they don&#8217;t want to feel stupid).</p>
<h3 id="88986ff5-79c5-4158-929c-6935834133e9">It works for&#8230;</h3>
<p id="14e9e6e6-784c-48b4-81ca-d3afab14b9b7"><strong>This copywriting technique is useful if you&#8217;re writing for a hobby or passion business</strong>, meaning a business that taps into someone&#8217;s interests and passions. Like, a business that sells sewing&#8230; things. Or bike&#8230; bits. These are usually industries that have jargon and people who are passionate about the industry will <em>love</em> being able to talk the talk. So, you can too.</p>
<h3 id="8ec3ffe9-a47a-47af-87c2-b2abb29d9ddc">Don&#8217;t let it fall flat</h3>
<p id="8e0c441b-0b9a-4d18-a938-ce82c2b046c3">The key to knowing if your copy will hit the mark is knowing who you are talking to.</p>
<p id="65f891ca-ec5d-471e-9c3e-e82c56064290">Start by defining your target audience (really clearly) and work backwards. <strong>Understand their stage of awareness </strong>and <strong>level of understanding about the topic</strong>. If you&#8217;re writing for audiences really early in their awareness, keep the language inclusive.</p>
<p id="b5d6ac8d-6992-421e-9d0f-bf53167f659c"><em>TIP:<a href="https://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PencilMonogramSML.png" data-cke-saved-href="https://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/PencilMonogramSML.png"> </a>These are two great questions for your copywriting brief!</em></p>
<p id="4d5ef491-c9bd-49bd-a789-5aef368da293">The danger of exclusion is excluding your intended audience. The key to knowing if your copy will hit the mark is knowing who you are talking to.</p>
<p id="ee4aeaf3-1d56-4222-807a-5df1b3860d2b">If you are writing copy aimed at IT systems administrators, don’t break the ideas down to high school computing. Conversely, don&#8217;t start talking to SEO beginners about complex search engine algorithms.</p>
<p>You can break all the copywriting rules to create exclusivity for an audience. But make sure they are actually the ones reading your copy!</p>
<p><em>Belinda </em></p>
<p><strong>P.S.</strong> A great way to attract the right kind of audience is to <strong>include your target market in your headline.</strong> It will grab their attention and let everyone just pass on by. Like this &#8230;</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Contemporary Art Lovers: Don’t miss out on this special preview sale</p>
<p style="text-align: left; padding-left: 30px;">Aspiring Copywriters: Learn copywriting skills that earn you $$$</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/geishas-taught-exclusion-copywriting/">Geishas and the secret power of exclusion in copywriting</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/geishas-taught-exclusion-copywriting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>2</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Transform your copywriting from a marching band into a Cuban party on the page</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/transform-your-copywriting-into-cuban-party-on-the-page/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/transform-your-copywriting-into-cuban-party-on-the-page/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 03 Jun 2018 21:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Useful Tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[exciting copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing copywriter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.copywritematters.com.au/?p=615</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been a copywriter for a while, you may have received client feedback asking you to make the copywriting “punchier/snappier/more exciting”. If you’ve ever heard this, smiled politely then wondered how the hell you were going to make that happen… well, this is the post for you! And it really is quite simple. If you [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/transform-your-copywriting-into-cuban-party-on-the-page/">Transform your copywriting from a marching band into a Cuban party on the page</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>If you’ve been a copywriter for a while, you may have received client feedback asking you to make the copywriting “punchier/snappier/more exciting”.</p>
<p>If you’ve ever heard this, smiled politely then wondered how the hell you were going to make that happen… well, this is the post for you!</p>
<p>And it really is quite simple. <strong>If you want your copywriting to feel more exciting, you have to create <em>an exciting rhythm</em>.</strong></p>
<p>The sentences you write and the words you use will create a beat for your reader.</p>
<p>Start with the length of your sentences. If all your sentences are roughly the same length, you&#8217;ve created a regular beat that could keep time for a marching band. Your reader begins to expect the ebb and flow of your words as they read and it can lull them into boredom.</p>
<p>To give add a spicy Cuban beat that puts a party on your page, write longer sentences mixed with really short ones.</p>
<p>Like this.</p>
<p>Yes!</p>
<p>One word sentences are a thing!</p>
<p>When you mix it up, you&#8217;re keeping your reader on their toes. And the stop and start? Well, it’s just more interesting to read.</p>
<p>And now it’s over to you…. Have you ever had this client request? How did you approach your copywriting in response? Or maybe you just do this as a matter of course. Do tell.</p>
<p><em>Belinda</em></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/transform-your-copywriting-into-cuban-party-on-the-page/">Transform your copywriting from a marching band into a Cuban party on the page</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/transform-your-copywriting-into-cuban-party-on-the-page/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Want copywriting x-ray vision? 3 lenses to reveal audience motives</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 31 May 2018 21:00:29 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=7975</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>As copywriters, we need to understand our readers. Or reader. Consensus is that we should always write to one person; and understand that one person quite intimately. It&#8217;s tempting to list their age, income and where they live but those details are usually irrelevant. The problem is that consumers usually don&#8217;t go about their shopping [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/">Want copywriting x-ray vision? 3 lenses to reveal audience motives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p id="05d34daf-1ec1-4588-b5e6-ab020290b063">As copywriters, we need to understand our readers. Or reader. Consensus is that we should always write to one person; and understand that one person quite intimately.</p>
<p id="fd1285ff-79c4-4f91-9cde-7201cfdae2ed">It&#8217;s tempting to list their age, income and where they live but those details are usually irrelevant.</p>
<blockquote>
<p id="a0053a6c-9a2e-497c-a934-5a229bf85cef">The problem is that consumers usually don&#8217;t go about their shopping by conforming to particular segments. Rather, they take life as it comes. And when faced with a job that needs doing, they essentially &#8220;hire&#8221; a product to do that job.</p>
<p>&#8220;&#8230;  the jobs-to-be-done point of view causes you to crawl into the skin of your customer and go with her as she goes about her day, always asking the question as she does something: Why did she do it that way?&#8221; <a href="https://hbswk.hbs.edu/item/clay-christensens-milkshake-marketing">Source</a>.</p></blockquote>
<h2>A story to illustrate.</h2>
<p id="f2f537a7-43c8-4f3f-bd85-56715e8f195d">Harvard Business School professor, Clayton Christensen, <a href="https://hbswk.hbs.edu/item/clay-christensens-milkshake-marketing">shared this case in his MBA course</a>.</p>
<p id="3625746a-cbd4-4c24-a5f0-ff3beb7d8280">A popular fast food restaurant wanted to boost sales of their milkshakes. To cut a long story short, they did some research found a surprising job the milkshakes were performing for customers.</p>
<blockquote id="a1238181-ecf0-49fc-b377-4230ccddeeea">
<p id="2b00e322-ceb1-4ab6-a5a9-62e54aeac044">&#8220;Most of them, it turned out, bought [the milkshake] to do a similar job,&#8221; Christensen writes. &#8220;They faced a long, boring commute and needed something to keep that extra hand busy and to make the commute more interesting. They weren&#8217;t yet hungry, but knew that they&#8217;d be hungry by 10 a.m.; they wanted to consume something now that would stave off hunger until noon. And they faced constraints: They were in a hurry, they were wearing work clothes, and they had (at most) one free hand.&#8221;</p>
<p id="e20973f9-19a8-4388-b9e9-365ce56eb037">The milkshake was hired in lieu of a bagel or doughnut because it was relatively tidy and appetite-quenching, and because trying to suck a thick liquid through a thin straw gave customers something to do with their boring commute.</p>
</blockquote>
<p id="4d4adb36-de26-42b3-b45d-f3b3a20f974e">While the motives of your target market might seem obvious, it’s worth digging a little deeper to see if that what’s really going on when they make the decision to buy.</p>
<p id="6b2770f0-3f3d-47b4-b296-e16b77c5044f"><strong>The lesson: Don’t just consider <em>what</em> your target is looking for. You must also think about <em>why</em> they are looking for it.</strong></p>
<h2>Powerful motives run deep</h2>
<p>When you can mirror readers’ thoughts and feelings, you show them that you <em>understand</em> them, and that generates feelings of trust and credibility. And when someone trusts you <strong>their barriers to your persuasion are way down.</strong></p>
<p>But understanding your audience can be hard. I mean, if they&#8217;re just like you, it&#8217;s easy but more often than not you&#8217;re writing copy to persuade an audience that&#8217;s entirely <em>unlike</em> you.</p>
<p>So how do you go about the task of understanding the why behind their actions?</p>
<p>This post covers three different lenses that can give you x-ray vision about your audiences&#8217; motives.</p>
<h3>Let&#8217;s begin with Bob Bly</h3>
<p>Copywriter Bob Bly (All Hail) has a fantastic list of motivators. He explains that people buy something:</p>
<table width="907">
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="464">
<ul>
<li><strong>To be liked</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be appreciated</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be right</strong></li>
<li><strong>To feel important</strong></li>
<li><strong>To make money</strong></li>
<li><strong>To save money</strong></li>
<li><strong>To save time</strong></li>
<li><strong>To make work easier</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be secure</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be attractive</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be sexy</strong></li>
</ul>
</td>
<td width="464">
<ul>
<li><strong>To be comfortable</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be distinctive</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be happy</strong></li>
<li><strong>To have fun</strong></li>
<li><strong>To gain knowledge</strong></li>
<li><strong>To be healthy</strong></li>
<li><strong>To gratify curiosity</strong></li>
<li><strong>For convenience</strong></li>
<li><strong>Out of fear</strong></li>
<li><strong>Out of greed</strong></li>
<li><strong>Out of guilt</strong></li>
</ul>
</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p>I really like the simplicity of these motives. We can all identify with them and they give us lots of different angles to work with.</p>
<p id="77f7e93c-22f7-427d-8143-b365dd546ede">Keep in mind that most people will usually have more than one motive.</p>
<p id="4b9421d0-008a-4570-b6f0-82ea8f2b3a96">When we buy a car, we might be buying it to be secure, to be comfortable and to make work easier. But dig a little deeper and our real motives are probably closer to being liked, loved and appreciated&#8230; to feel <em>important</em> and to be <em>attractive</em>.</p>
<p id="a1b0acfb-31cb-4197-aaf5-ee7045016378">It depends on the car of course. My beat up Honda CRV will live cultures growing in my kids&#8217; car seats&#8230; not so much. That baby really was all about convenience.</p>
<h2>Let&#8217;s dig deeper into marketing theory</h2>
<p>In marketing theory, all those motives can be broken down into the five basic priorities that drive our decisions.</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/MaslowsHeirarchyofNeeds.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-7976 " src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/MaslowsHeirarchyofNeeds.jpg" alt="Maslows Heirarchy of Needs" width="742" height="462" srcset="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/MaslowsHeirarchyofNeeds.jpg 836w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/MaslowsHeirarchyofNeeds-300x187.jpg 300w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/MaslowsHeirarchyofNeeds-504x314.jpg 504w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/05/MaslowsHeirarchyofNeeds-200x125.jpg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 742px) 100vw, 742px" /></a></p>
<h4>This is a classic marketing diagram known as Maslow’s Hierarchy of Needs.</h4>
<ol>
<li>First, we look after our physiological needs. We make sure we have shelter, food, water and warmth so <strong>we can survive.</strong></li>
<li>Once they are taken care of, we look to <strong>make sure we are safe.</strong> Safety could be lock and key protection or something more high-level like contractual safety.</li>
<li>When we can survive and we’re safe, we look to fill our <strong>need for social interaction</strong> and love. <strong>Following that, our self-esteem.</strong></li>
<li>Finally, when we have what we need to survive, we’re safe, we have a sense of belonging and our self-esteem is being taken care of… then we <strong>look to achieve our potential as humans.</strong></li>
</ol>
<h2>Let&#8217;s end with some research</h2>
<p>The last model I want to share with you was created by Ernest Dichter, known as “the father of motivational research”.</p>
<p>He mapped out 12 motives that drive our desires, fears and our shopping:</p>
<table>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Power/Masculinity/Virility</strong></td>
<td width="539">Strength and dominance!</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Security</strong></td>
<td width="539">Safety as well as home comfort</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Eroticism </strong></td>
<td width="539">Sexuality and desire. Sex sells!</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Cleanliness/Moral Purity</strong></td>
<td width="539">Cleanliness isn’t just functional, moral purity is often implied in the colours and imagery used</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Social Acceptance</strong></td>
<td width="539">Companionship, approval and love</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Individuality</strong></td>
<td width="539">The desire to be unique</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Status</strong></td>
<td width="539">Feeling important, respected and successful</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Femininity</strong></td>
<td width="539">All things associated with being feminine</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Reward</strong></td>
<td width="539">Maximising our payoff</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Mastery over environment</strong></td>
<td width="539">Competence and mastery. Can be closely related to <em>reward</em> and <em>power</em>.</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Disalienation </strong></td>
<td width="539">The desire to feel connectedness to things. <em>This is often seen in fast food outlets. The food can be a little different around the world but there is a sameness that we crave.</em></td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td width="357"><strong>Magic and mystery</strong></td>
<td width="539">Powers unseen, surprises and moods</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p id="0e315325-ce11-4fc1-bcb0-8998272fb233">You can see the parallels with Bob Bly&#8217;s list and Maslow&#8217;s Heirarchy. Esteem&#8230; acceptance&#8230; security&#8230; mastery&#8230;</p>
<h2>3 lenses = deeper understanding</h2>
<p><strong>The lesson: when you understand what <em>really</em> motivates someone to act, you can override their rational brain. </strong></p>
<p>That&#8217;s the one telling them NOT to buy. Instead, you talk to the little voice that’s <em>really</em> running the show.</p>
<p id="4c30269e-922d-40a0-9769-56bac21c3c08">When you look at your target reader through multiple lenses, their motives develop subtleties that give them depth. That makes them a little easier to &#8216;hear&#8217; when we get to trying to capture the right tone of voice.</p>
<p>Together, these models give you different lenses to see your reader through, which means lots of different ways to consider their motives.</p>
<p id="0b5a30ae-3b3e-460f-8ec4-13ec4112af55">Take some time with this. Dig deep into the why. Your life experience counts for a lot here.</p>
<h2>Your task</h2>
<p>Before you sit down to write a headline, call to action or an entire website of copy, take some time to consider what is <em>really</em> motivating your audience (beyond the obvious rational motives).</p>
<p><strong>And dig deep.</strong> Because the motives that live deeply within in us usually have the most power.</p>
<p>When you understand them, you can choose <a href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriter-words-that-sell/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">copywriting language</a> that cuts straight to the heart of the matter.</p>
<p><em>Belinda</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/">Want copywriting x-ray vision? 3 lenses to reveal audience motives</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-audience-motive-lenses/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>I hand copied sales messages for 180 days straight&#8230; Here’s what happened…</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hand-copied-sales-messages/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hand-copied-sales-messages/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Mar 2018 20:00:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miguel Campaner]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sales letters]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=13468</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a guest post by Miguel Campaner, Product Launch Copywriter and Consultant. Over to you Miguel! What if I told you there’s a way to become a world-class copywriter 10X faster? You only have to commit some time each day. Plus, it costs absolutely nothing upfront. You’ll be able to charge higher fees. Gain respect faster. Enter [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hand-copied-sales-messages/">I hand copied sales messages for 180 days straight&#8230; Here’s what happened…</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a guest post by <span class="entry-author"><span class="entry-author-name">Miguel Campaner, Product Launch Copywriter and Consultant.</span></span></em> <em>Over to you Miguel!</em></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What if I told you there’s a way to become a world-class copywriter 10X faster? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You only have to commit some time each day. Plus, it costs absolutely nothing upfront. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ll be able to charge higher fees. Gain respect faster. Enter the “A-list.” And be one of the most sought-after copywriters in your industry. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Sounds too good to be true, right? </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Well, think again. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In his seminal book, </span><i><span style="font-weight: 400;">The Boron Letters</span></i><span style="font-weight: 400;">, Gary Halbert taught his son, Bond, how to become a skilled copywriter fast. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gary didn’t tell Bond to buy a book, take a writing course, or attend a seminar (unlike most copywriters would suggest today).</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Instead, he said this:</span></p>
<p><b>“The best way to become a good writer i</b><b>s by&#8230;</b><b>writing good writing!”</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Gary Halbert told his son to copy proven ads by hand. Every single day. Gary said this was his secret for writing million dollar promotions. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">No one questioned his wisdom then. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">After all, he was crowned by legends like Jay Abraham and John Carlton as “The Best Copywriter Of All Time.”</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Today, it’s a bit different. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Many emerging copywriters achieved success without hand copying sales letters. This is what they teach their copy cubs. Those copy cubs teach their cubs&#8230;and so on and so forth. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, I get why many copywriters advice against it. I&#8217;ve talked to them, asked their opinions, and&#8230;</span></p>
<h2><b>Here are their best reasons to NOT copy sales letters by hand</b></h2>
<h3><b>1. You’re studying old sales messages</b></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">We can all agree that sales messages evolve over time. What worked in the past won’t probably work today. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The market’s level of sophistication has increased. Customers are now more sceptical. The competition is fiercer than ever. For example: “Lose 10 lbs in 8 weeks” looked enticing in the 60s. It would be ignored now.</span></p>
<p><b>2. Practising in a vacuum</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">How do you know you’re getting better or not? What’s your measuring stick? </span></p>
<p><b>3. Better to write sales letters and let the market be the judge</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is one of the strongest arguments I&#8217;ve heard. It’s better to write your own sales copy and test it in the market. Put your skin in the game. Let your market decide if you&#8217;re good or not.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All good points right?</span></p>
<h2><strong>Now, there is only one argument WHY you should follow Gary Halbert’s advice. </strong></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">To be honest, it’s the only argument you need. </span></p>
<p><b>Copying sales letters by hand etches brilliant and profitable sales copy in your mind&#8230;</b></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Writing by hand activates more areas of your brain than reading, typing, or reciting. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">According to French Psychologist Stanislas Dehaene, learning is made easier if you write your lessons by hand. Yes, typing is easier. Yet, it doesn’t cement the lessons in your brain like handwriting can. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ll find hundreds of scientific research like this. All pointing to one conclusion. Handwriting can improve your critical thinking, language, working memory, reasoning, and even certain parts of your brain.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">So Gary Halbert’s advice actually has a scientific basis. </span></p>
<blockquote><p>All-in, copying great ads by hand is hard to argue against!</p>
<p><em>Roy Furr, BreakthroughMarketingSecrets.com</em></p></blockquote>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In short, copying ads by hand helps you learn copywriting on a subconscious level. You’ll internalize the ads better. You digest every word. Pay close attention to the different elements that make the ad great. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you can tattoo great, masterful copywriting into your brain, you’d do it, right?</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Unfortunately, many beginners do it the wrong way. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s why today I’m going to show you the RIGHT way to follow Gary Halbert’s advice.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Before that, I’m going to tell you what&#8217;s in store for you. What you&#8217;ll gain if you do this.</span></p>
<h2><b>Here’s what happened when I copied proven sales letters by hand for 180 days straight</b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The sales messages I hand copied were from a mix of old and modern advertisements and sales letters.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">From Gary Halbert to Eugene Schwartz to Gary Bencivenga, John Caples to Ramit Sethi’s sales letters&#8230;Roy Furr’s&#8230;Ben Settle’s&#8230;Joe Sugarman’s&#8230;Matt Furey’s&#8230;and even some of Robert Collier’s work. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">All in all, I may have hand copied 50+ sales letters for 180 days straight.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, I didn’t spend hours handwriting them. I wrote 30-45 minutes per day. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Once the alarm rings, I stop copying.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">In that process, I learned:</span></p>
<p><strong>1.  How to construct winning sales messages<br />
</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hand copying allows you to pay close attention to each word, phrase, and sentence you write. So you’ll better understand an ad’s strengths. See more carefully which parts moved you emotionally or compelled you to act. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">You can actually break down the ad and analyze it WHILE you’re copying.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">In essence, you’re not just hand copying or rewriting. You’re actually studying it more intently.  </span></p>
<p><strong>2. How to write “flow-lessly”</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Your sales copy should flow like the Niagara Falls. Every sentence’s job is to make sure you read the next. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">When you handwrite classic space ads, you’ll see what I mean. Every word deserved to be there. That’s why the transitions from lead to sales argument to offer were as smooth as butter. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">You were reading the headline, the next thing you know you’re about to order what they’re selling. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Joe Sugarman calls this the “slippery slide.” You’ll see how this is applied when you start copying old space ads by hand.</span></p>
<p><strong>3. The successful writing frameworks<br />
</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">The more you hand copy ads and sales letters, the more you’ll see the same sequences, phrases, and frameworks popping up. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ll see what words they used, how they started their copy, how they presented their offer, how they closed, their call-to-action, and many more. </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">For example, Gary Halbert’s Star-Story-Solution framework. An extremely persuasive framework that’s brought in millions.</span></p>
<p><strong>4. How great copywriters think</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Copywriting is more than writing ads, emails, scripts, or sales letters. We need to develop the Big Idea, determine the market’s dominant emotion, sophistication level, awareness level, and so much more.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you hand copy old ads and modern sales letters, you’ll see how great copywriters tie it all together.</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">You’ll start noticing their sales hooks, big ideas, and irresistible offers. A big plus if it’s in your industry. You can borrow an idea or two. </span></p>
<p><strong>5. To start collecting a swipe file</strong><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Every great copywriter has a swipe file. The legends have it. The A-listers have it. Why shouldn’t you? </span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;"><br />
</span><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hand copying not only lets you understand these sales letters on a subconscious level. You can also look to them for inspiration, when you’re stuck or when writer’s block is simply smacking you in the face.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Now, this is all great. But did my copywriting skills improve? Hell yes!</span></p>
<p><a href="https://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage1.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-13494 " src="https://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage1.jpg" alt="Look at these copywriting results image" width="712" height="636" srcset="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage1.jpg 931w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage1-300x268.jpg 300w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage1-768x686.jpg 768w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage1-504x450.jpg 504w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage1-200x179.jpg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 712px) 100vw, 712px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s why hand copying fits in the copywriting training hierarchy. Here’s where:</span></p>
<p><a href="https://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage2.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-13495" src="https://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage2.jpg" alt="Heirarchy of copywriting skills image" width="602" height="401" srcset="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage2.jpg 602w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage2-300x200.jpg 300w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage2-504x336.jpg 504w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/03/Miguelblogimage2-200x133.jpg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 602px) 100vw, 602px" /></a></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>The most affordable copywriting education is hand copying.</strong> You can find hundreds of ads written by great copywriters on the Internet. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Hand copying lets you know what great sales copy looks like. Books and courses teach you the nuts and bolts. The intricacies of forming sales messages. How to write a sales letter, email, script from start to finish.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>On the first two levels, you’re not even getting paid yet.</strong> You’re only learning. When you step on the third level, that’s when you should reach a level of competency. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>The third level is where many newbies quit.</strong> They can’t face the fact they’re not good. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re on this level right now, treasure every moment. Welcome every praise or criticism. It will be good for you in the long run. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Copywriters should have no egos. The earlier you accept this, the sooner you can reach the top. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The fourth level&#8230;If you want to invest in higher learning, get a coach or a mentor. Every 7-Figure copywriter has been coached or mentored by an 8-figure copywriter. This is expensive, but it’s available.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">The last step is starting your own business. The best-of-the-best (like Gary Bencivenga, John Carlton, Kevin Roger) stopped writing sales copy and built a business. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>This is where great copywriters learn the most.</strong> They learn from risk, failures, and missed opportunities. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re not here yet, don’t worry. You will reach the top if you stick to the process. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">That’s why you have to know what the CORRECT process is. </span></p>
<h2><b>The correct way to copy ads by hand to 10X your copywriting skill </b></h2>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Everybody should be doing this. I know 6-figure copywriters who still hand copy ads and sales letters from time to time. It keeps them sharp. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re a beginner, there’s no reason you shouldn’t do this. If you’re an experienced copywriter that wants to get better fast, do this too. </span></p>
<h3><span style="font-weight: 400;"><strong>Step 1: Find high converting sales letters.</strong> </span></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Go to swiped.co. The site has hundreds of proven ads and sales letters. </span></p>
<h3><strong>Step 2: Hand copy sales letters for 30-60 minutes</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">This is the easy and fun part. </span></p>
<h3><strong>Step 3: Write sales copy</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Write an email or short sales letter. Anything. Just write. </span></p>
<h3><strong>Step 4: Read books about copywriting</strong></h3>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you’re brand new, buy Joe Sugarman’s <em>Adweek Copywriting Handbook</em>. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Learning is applying. Without application, learning on a subconscious level is useless. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Start hand copying. Once you feel you’re good enough, write an ad, a sales page, or an email. Test it in your market. Sell something/</span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">If you want to achieve a level of “competency” or have enough confidence faster, start handwriting sales messages. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">Do this for 30 days. Compare what you wrote on Day 1 with Day 30. If your skills didn’t improve, stop. If it did, keep doing it. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-weight: 400;">What do you have to lose? </span></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hand-copied-sales-messages/">I hand copied sales messages for 180 days straight&#8230; Here’s what happened…</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hand-copied-sales-messages/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>7</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>7 ways to write about generic topics, but sound totally awesome</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/7-ways-write-generic-topics-sound-totally-awesome/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/7-ways-write-generic-topics-sound-totally-awesome/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 20:00:15 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Victoria Greene]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[boring topic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[generic topic]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[guest post]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Victoria Greene]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=13007</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This is a guest post by Victoria Greene, a branding consultant and freelance writer. Take it away Victoria!  As a copywriter, you’ve probably written your fair share of vaguely generic articles. In the online world, we often see the same topics covered time and again – not necessarily word-for-word, but close enough that you only [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/7-ways-write-generic-topics-sound-totally-awesome/">7 ways to write about generic topics, but sound totally awesome</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>This is a guest post by Victoria Greene, a branding consultant and freelance writer. Take it away Victoria! </em></p>
<p>As a copywriter, you’ve probably written your fair share of vaguely generic articles.</p>
<p>In the online world, we often see the same topics covered time and again – not necessarily word-for-word, but close enough that you only need read one such article on the subject. Some topics are simply not very interesting to write about – at least, perhaps not to you. But if it’s your job to write about them, how can you take these generic topics and approach them in an interesting way?</p>
<p>Here are 7 techniques that I like to use to give an otherwise generic subject a fresh lease of life.</p>
<p><em>Related reading: </em><a href="https://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-e64-copywriting-formulas/"><em>Copywriting formulas: Smart copywriting? Or cheating?</em></a></p>
<h2>The unexpected comparison</h2>
<p>An unlikely comparison that still somehow works makes for a more interesting and fiesty read than your standard point-by-point article. All you need to do this well is to become a master of justification. As long as you can justify <em>why</em> something is like something else, in a few different ways, preferably with examples, then you have a logical thread to follow.</p>
<p>For example, I once wrote an article on <em>Why Designing A Website Is Like Building A House</em>. Because in many ways it is – you have to find the right location (hosting), you have to make plans, you have to consider efficiency and usability, and you need to know when is the right time to get professionals involved. It’s obviously not exactly the same process, but there are enough parallels for the article to make sense and have value.</p>
<p>The unexpected comparison allows you to have a little more fun as a writer. Look around you for metaphors, patterns, or interesting points of comparison. Have a go at pitting surprising things against each other to <a href="https://www.grammarly.com/blog/bland-writing/">add a little more flavour to your writing</a>.</p>
<h2>The time limit</h2>
<p>Maybe you’ve been asked to write an article about a generic topic, such as how to reduce belly fat, or tips for becoming more productive. These articles don’t really need writing – there are thousands of them out there already. But here’s a thing: people are lazy. We all want to have flatter stomachs and higher productivity. And we’d all rather have these things sooner.</p>
<p>So if you’re writing an article like this, try working with a time frame. Example time frames:</p>
<ul>
<li>In Under 1 Hour</li>
<li>With An Hour A Day</li>
<li>In Less Than A Week</li>
<li>In Exactly One Week</li>
<li>In One Month</li>
<li>In Less Than 30 Days</li>
<li>In 3 Months etc etc.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>The time frame makes the task feel more achievable and concrete.</strong> And it means you have to condense each task or step to its bare minimum, focusing on the quick wins. Considering the vast majority of us are time-poor, working within a time limit is a great way to get more eyes on your content. It can also bring up surprising points of comparison.</p>
<h2>The unconventional/cult character guide</h2>
<p>Just like with an unexpected comparison, writing an ‘unconventional’ or ‘cult character’ guide to a generic topic instantly makes it sound more interesting. And again, it’s easy to do. All you need is justification. Note: this sort of thing tends to work better for more playful, informal brands.</p>
<p>This <a href="https://www.buzzblogger.com/oprah-winfrey-guide-to-social-media/">BuzzBlogger article</a>, The Oprah Winfrey Guide to Social Media could have simply been called ‘How to Create a Social Media Marketing Plan’. A tired title for a tired topic. Giving it a topical celebrity framework gives this piece a more intriguing and interesting angle.</p>
<p>There’s really no lack of possibilities. And if you can pick an angle that’s relevant to your niche, even better. If you write about beauty products, why not try ‘How to Do Your Makeup Like Kylie Jenner’? Or if you write about film, what about ‘The Alfred Hitchcock Guide to Writing Screenplays’?</p>
<p>You can’t go wrong with a good ‘unconventional guide to &#8230;’ – unless of course, you forget to add anything unconventional.  What about The Unconventional Guide To Freelancing, or The Unconventional Guide To Getting Signed By A Record Label for starters?</p>
<h2>The personal story</h2>
<p>One way to be sure you are covering fresh ground is to tell a personal story, or at least include relevant anecdotes. Even if you’re experiences are not entirely unique, it’s more interesting to hear about what someone else went through than what might happen ‘in theory’. Plus, you will have legitimate examples to back up your points.</p>
<p>Because humans love storytelling, hearing a first person perspective is a great way to draw readers in. So what can you add of your own personal experience to the generic article you’re writing?</p>
<p>To give an example, I recently opened an Oberlo dropshipping store. According to all the studies that I researched in advance — this should have been a smooth and easy process. But of course, even the simplest process in theory can throw up obstacles in practice. Obstacles like customers struggling to find what they want (even when it’s right there in front of them), print samples not coming out as you expect them to, and even one unhappy customer airing her grievances publicly on social media.</p>
<p>Instead of putting a PR-friendly spin on everything, I opened up online about the challenges I’d been having with my store. I shared real and raw outtakes of my entrepreneur journey (like the 2 AM blog post writing or the time all my shipments went out wrong). It was a great way to make topics that have already been covered <em>like a million times </em>seem more fresh and engaging.</p>
<p>As well as going into detail about how tough the entrepreneurial journey can be, I added cool storytelling elements to my product listings in order to help them stand out. I went into detail about how the products could themselves become part of someone’s life and personal story. A story is a great way to create a more direct relationship with your reader.</p>
<p><strong>It’s helpful to share real-life experiences of what works and doesn’t work. This is how we learn. Your experiences, whether good or bad, could prove useful reading for someone else. At the very least, it stops you churning out an identikit piece of writing.</strong></p>
<h2>Messing with formats</h2>
<p>An article isn’t the only way to cover a topic. And frankly, sometimes it’s not the best way. If lots of content already exists about your given generic topic, can you take that information and present it differently?</p>
<p>What if you took that information and turned it into some sort of graphic? Does it lend itself to a table or diagram? What if you could make it into a short video or podcast? Buzzfeed has a habit of using memes and GIFs throughout its content – silly yes, but their traffic speaks volumes.</p>
<p>You can also use tone to sound different to other generic articles. Perhaps write more conversationally, breaking the copy right down.</p>
<p>Like this.</p>
<p>There are lots of written formats to play with as well – numbered lists, step-by-step guides, how-tos – don’t let yourself feel constrained by everything that has gone before.</p>
<p>Some <a href="http://contentmarketinginstitute.com/2016/04/fresh-content-formats/">fresh content formats you may want to try</a>.</p>
<h2>Picking a thing</h2>
<p>Generic articles are often so-called because they skim lightly over a subject, without really getting into the nitty-gritty. They provide an overview. So if you must cover a certain topic that has been done to death already, why not take one element and write in more depth about that?</p>
<p>Say you want to write about digital marketing. Pick just one element of that – maybe Facebook Advertising. You can then break that down even more, perhaps looking at split testing, sequential advertising, social ad formats, analytics, or whatever.</p>
<p><strong>The more niche you can go, the more expert you will appear.</strong> <strong>And it gives you leeway to write several different articles, all about digital marketing, rather than just the one.</strong></p>
<h2>Newsjacking</h2>
<p>Finally, another way to liven up a generic topic is to <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Newsjack">newsjack</a> – make the subject relevant to something else that’s happening in the world right now and is already on people’s radars.</p>
<p>As I write this, here are a few things that are happening:</p>
<ul>
<li>Trump appeared to forget the words to the National Anthem</li>
<li>North Korea is considering sending a team to the Olympics</li>
<li>Oprah Winfrey made an electrifying speech at the Golden Globes</li>
<li>Scientists have developed a bionic hand with a sense of touch</li>
</ul>
<p>It’s worth noting that news material should be used sensitively. Don’t use an emotional story to make a frivolous point in the name of getting clicks. But done right, it’s a great way to jump on pretty much any bandwagon you want to get involved in. Did I mention justification?</p>
<p>For example, based on the events above, you could write something relevant and timely such as:</p>
<ul>
<li>Lost For Words: Cognitive Impairment &amp; Other Causes of Poor Memory</li>
<li>The Oprah Winfrey Guide to Sensational Public Speaking</li>
<li>Electric Cars &amp; Bionic Limbs: The Bright and Crazy Future of 3D Printing</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>So for your own sake and that of your readers, next time you are handed the most generic brief of your life, I urge you to consider unusual ways of presenting the information – even if at first glance it seems impossible.</strong></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/7-ways-write-generic-topics-sound-totally-awesome/">7 ways to write about generic topics, but sound totally awesome</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/7-ways-write-generic-topics-sound-totally-awesome/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy E68: Copywriting in sickness and in health</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-e68-copywriter-in-sickness-and-health/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-e68-copywriter-in-sickness-and-health/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2018 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=12842</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;I feel so ill but I have deadlines to meet.&#8221; Sound familiar? If you&#8217;ve ever experienced a nasty cold or flu, a face-slapping hangover because you forgot you&#8217;re not 20 or you have to step away from your business due to a planned stay in a hospital, your copywriting business needs to go on. Or [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-e68-copywriter-in-sickness-and-health/">Hot Copy E68: Copywriting in sickness and in health</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;I feel so ill but I have deadlines to meet.&#8221; Sound familiar?</p>
<p>If you&#8217;ve ever experienced a nasty cold or flu, a face-slapping hangover because you forgot you&#8217;re not 20 or you have to step away from your business due to a planned stay in a hospital, your copywriting business needs to go on.</p>
<p>Or does it?</p>
<p>In this episode of the Hot Copy podcast, Kate and I talk about handling unexpected and planned illnesses and how to keep clients and your bank balance happy.</p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;"><strong>We dig into:</strong></span></p>
<ul>
<li>Kate and Belinda’s experience with planned and unplanned business outages</li>
<li>Our top 3 tips for helping your business survive unexpected illness</li>
<li>How you can prepare yourself and your business</li>
<li>Our sage advice to prevent major kerfuffles taking your business offline</li>
</ul>
<h3>Listen to the show</h3>
<p>To listen to the show on <a href="http://apple.co/1Lbiirx" target="_blank" rel="noopener">iTunes</a> (search for Hot Copy), <a href="http://bit.ly/2nMFfsR" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Stitcher</a>, or the <a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/e68-copywriting-sickness-health" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Hot Copy podcast website</a>.</p>
<p><a class="button" href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/e68-copywriting-sickness-health">Take me to the Hot Copy website</a></p>
<h3>Share the pod love!</h3>
<p>If you like what you’re hearing on Hot Copy, the best way to support the show is to take just a few seconds to leave a rating and / or comment over on <a href="http://www.itunes.com/">iTunes</a> or <a href="http://www.stitcher.com/podcast/hot-copy?refid=stpr">Stitcher</a>. Thanks!</p>
<p>Oh and big hugs to Leigh Gree from the USA their five-star review.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Let&#8217;s be real here..</p>
<p><a href="https://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Copywriting-in-sickness-and-in-health-meme.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-12872 size-full" src="https://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Copywriting-in-sickness-and-in-health-meme.png" alt="Being a copywriter when you're ill be like" width="640" height="640" srcset="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Copywriting-in-sickness-and-in-health-meme.png 640w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Copywriting-in-sickness-and-in-health-meme-150x150.png 150w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Copywriting-in-sickness-and-in-health-meme-300x300.png 300w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Copywriting-in-sickness-and-in-health-meme-504x504.png 504w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Copywriting-in-sickness-and-in-health-meme-470x470.png 470w, http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/Copywriting-in-sickness-and-in-health-meme-200x200.png 200w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>Happy listening!</p>
<p>Belinda and Kate<em> (your Hot Copy hosts)</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-e68-copywriter-in-sickness-and-health/">Hot Copy E68: Copywriting in sickness and in health</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-e68-copywriter-in-sickness-and-health/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
