<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Copywrite Matters</title>
	<atom:link href="http://copywritematters.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://copywritematters.com</link>
	<description>Copywriting courses, coaching and content</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2016 11:57:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.3.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Hot Copy podcast #39: Our favourite creative and business podcasts</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-39-fav-podcasts/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-39-fav-podcasts/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creative podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot copy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9510</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In this week’s pod we’re talking about our favourite podcasts and how they help us become better writers, better business people and better humans. We think you’re going to love this episode because it’s packed full of some of iTunes best. We’re sharing our faves podcasts, what we learn from them and how we use [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-39-fav-podcasts/">Hot Copy podcast #39: Our favourite creative and business podcasts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5440" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>In this week’s pod we’re talking about our favourite podcasts and how they help us become better writers, better business people and better humans.</p>
<p>We think you’re going to love this episode because it’s packed full of some of iTunes best. We’re sharing our faves podcasts, what we learn from them and how we use them to grow and improve our businesses.</p>
<p>Tune in to learn:</p>
<ul>
<li>Our favourite business shows</li>
<li>Our favourite story telling shows</li>
<li>Why we love podcasts</li>
<li>When we think is the best time to listen</li>
<li>How to use podcast listening as a way to improve your business.</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe style="border: none;" src="//html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/4790207/height/360/width/640/theme/standard-mini/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/autoplay/no/preload/no/no_addthis/no/direction/backward/no-cache/true/" width="356" height="356" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>You can also listen on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/our-favourite-creative-and-business-podcasts" target="_blank">The Hot Copy podcast website</a> &lt;&lt; lots of extra resources here!</li>
</ul>
<p>If you like what you’re hearing on Hot Copy, the best way to support the show is to take just a few seconds to leave a rating and / or comment over on iTunes or Stitcher. Thanks!</p>
<p>We read out a review at the end of each show and today, we’re giving a shout out to Matt Fenwick!</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Our-favourite-creative-and-business-podcasts-meme.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-9508" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Our-favourite-creative-and-business-podcasts-meme-300x300.png" alt="Our Hot Copy meme for this podcast episode!" width="393" height="393" /></a></p>
<h3>Links mentioned in this article:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://thisiscriminal.com/" target="_blank">This is Criminal</a></li>
<li><a href="http://revisionisthistory.com/" target="_blank">Revisionist History</a></li>
<li><a href="https://serialpodcast.org/" target="_blank">Serial</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.flyingsolo.com.au/podcast" target="_blank">Flying Solo Podcast</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.thisamericanlife.org/podcast" target="_blank">This American Life</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.psychotactics.com/podcast/" target="_blank">Three Month Vacation podcast</a></li>
<li><a href="http://rainmaker.fm/shows/" target="_blank">Rainmaker FM</a> (Copyblogger pods out of the wazoo)</li>
<li><a href="http://qi.com/podcast/" target="_blank">There is no such thing as a fish</a></li>
<li><a href="http://nerdist.com/podcasts/nerdist-podcast-channel/" target="_blank">The Nerdist</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.bbc.co.uk/programmes/p02pc9pj/episodes/downloads" target="_blank">BBC 4 Friday Night Comedy</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-39-fav-podcasts/">Hot Copy podcast #39: Our favourite creative and business podcasts</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-39-fav-podcasts/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy podcast #38: Your HOT copywriting questions answered!</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-questions/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-questions/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot copy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[q&a]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9490</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Every now and then we host a very special Hot Copy episode and invite our listeners to send us their questions. This is one of those episodes! Sit back, relax and listen to our best answers to some questions you might even have wondered about. Thanks to Kylie Saunder, Johanna Kohler (Compelling Copy), Sarah Winterbine, [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-questions/">Hot Copy podcast #38: Your HOT copywriting questions answered!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5440" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>Every now and then we host a very special Hot Copy episode and invite our listeners to send us their questions. This is one of those episodes!</p>
<p>Sit back, relax and listen to our best answers to some questions you might even have wondered about.</p>
<p>Thanks to <a href="http://kyliesaunder.com/" target="_blank">Kylie Saunder</a>, Johanna Kohler (<a href="http://www.compellingcopy.com.au/" target="_blank">Compelling Copy</a>), <a href="https://www.facebook.com/Sarah-Winterbine-520365148161297/" target="_blank">Sarah Winterbine</a>, Lisa Cropman (<a href="http://thewordnest.com.au/" target="_blank">The Word Nest</a>), <a href="http://www.kellynicoleodonnell.com/" target="_blank">Kelly O’Donnell</a>,<a href="https://angeladenly.com.au/" target="_blank"> Angela Denly</a> and Jenny De Lacy (<a href="http://writingworksvic.com.au/" target="_blank">Writing Works</a>) for their questions!</p>
<p><strong>Tune in to learn:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>How to deal with requests to “polish” copy that has already been written</li>
<li>How to get a copywriting brief out of a tight lipped client</li>
<li>What we really think of online headline writing tools</li>
<li>How to plan for multiple, concurrent projects</li>
<li>And whether it’s better to outsource your own copywriting</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe style="border: none;" src="//html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/4790166/height/360/width/640/theme/standard-mini/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/autoplay/no/preload/no/no_addthis/no/direction/backward/no-cache/true/" width="368" height="368" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>You can also listen on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/your-hot-copywriting-questions-answered/" target="_blank">The Hot Copy podcast website</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If you like what you’re hearing on Hot Copy, the best way to support the show is to take just a few seconds to leave a rating and / or comment over on iTunes or Stitcher. Thanks!</p>
<p>We read out a review at the end of each show and today, we’re giving a shout out to Newbie Writer!</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Your-HOT-copywriting-questions-answered-meme.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-9491" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Your-HOT-copywriting-questions-answered-meme.png" alt="Copywriting podcast meme YEAH" width="440" height="440" /></a></p>
<h3>Links mentioned in this article:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://coschedule.com/" target="_blank">CoSchedule headline tool</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.portent.com/tools/title-maker" target="_blank">Portent content ideas generator</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-questions/">Hot Copy podcast #38: Your HOT copywriting questions answered!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-questions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is your creative well running dry? Proven tips to stimulate your creative self for better business</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/creative-well-running-dry-proven-tips-stimulate-creative-self-better-business/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/creative-well-running-dry-proven-tips-stimulate-creative-self-better-business/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 20:00:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[creativity tips]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9469</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>I don’t know about you, but I’m pooped. The year usually seems to race by, but right now, as we approach Christmas, time is moving like molasses. I feel like I’ve been laying tracks (figurative business tracks, that is) as fast as I can, yet I’m always getting through my to-do list just ahead of [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/creative-well-running-dry-proven-tips-stimulate-creative-self-better-business/">Is your creative well running dry? Proven tips to stimulate your creative self for better business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Creativityblogimage.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-9473" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/11/Creativityblogimage.png" alt="Creativity blog image" width="543" height="455" /></a></p>
<p>I don’t know about you, but I’m pooped.</p>
<p>The year usually seems to race by, but right now, as we approach Christmas, time is moving like molasses. I feel like I’ve been laying tracks (figurative business tracks, that is) as fast as I can, yet I’m always getting through my to-do list just ahead of my deadlines.</p>
<p>My brain feels like Gromit in the final chase scene of Wallace and Gromit.</p>
<p><iframe class="giphy-embed" src="//giphy.com/embed/11upydmB42l0Iw" width="480" height="270" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://giphy.com/gifs/11upydmB42l0Iw">via GIPHY</a></p>
<p>It’s exciting. It’s invigorating. But, you can’t run an engine at full speed forever, and I keep popping my head up to see Christmas as the end of this race. I am <em>really</em> looking forward to putting my “out of office” on this year.</p>
<p>Part of the reason is that <strong>my creativity feels a little wrung out.</strong></p>
<p>I think copywriters and designers suffer from creative burnout regularly <em>as ideas are our business</em>. But, whether you’re a creative type or not, it’s important to keep the ideas factory you call your brain working at peak efficiency.</p>
<p>One of my tips to avoid creative burnout is to give myself <strong>enough time to be creative.</strong> Don’t just let your brain recover in a pool of wine and roast dinners. Give yourself this time every day.</p>
<p><strong>But, what does that really mean?</strong></p>
<p><em>The Artist’s Way</em> is a book by Julia Cameron. A lot of people know this book because the process of unleashing your creative self isn’t just for artists. Almost every successful person I know (or aspire to know) has read this book and put some of its practises into place.</p>
<h3>Write morning pages</h3>
<p>Start each day with unstructured writing time. Don’t write a book or a blog. Just set a timer and write whatever pops into your head—without stopping.</p>
<p>I find this process <strong>incredibly efficient at decluttering my brain.</strong></p>
<p>I have a terrible habit of looking at my phone when I wake up, which usually means I jolt my brain awake with social media posts to read or respond to and emails I received overnight. That’s not great for meditation (my other morning ritual).</p>
<p>Writing my morning pages helps me to clear the slate of what is essentially brain clutter.</p>
<p>Now, morning pages and meditation might seem a bit too Zen for you, but if you really want to give your brain the space it needs to be creative, then find your own way to clear the slate of low-priority or non-urgent things that are screaming for your attention but don’t actually need it.</p>
<p><iframe class="giphy-embed" src="//giphy.com/embed/DB2oahQFa0qeQ" width="480" height="269" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p><a href="http://giphy.com/gifs/finding-nemo-roman-reigns-dean-ambrose-DB2oahQFa0qeQ">via GIPHY</a></p>
<p>Maybe it’s a run with music. Maybe it’s an email widget that doesn’t deliver emails until you begin work. Whatever is it, stop the chatter that’s constantly invading your creative space.</p>
<h3>Schedule creative project time</h3>
<p>The next part of the time equation is making sure your copywriting project timeline supports creative thinking.</p>
<p>You need time to put yourself in your clients’ shoes, mull over their frustrations and their challenges and consider potential solutions from different angles. While you have to put a cap on your brainstorming time, your copywriting project schedule does need to factor it in if you don’t want to take disastrous shortcuts.</p>
<p>Or more commonly, <strong>write bland and uninteresting copy</strong> because you don’t have time to do better.</p>
<h3>Make creative life time</h3>
<p>An extension of giving your brain the space to actually be creative is <strong>making sure your life supports creative thinking.</strong></p>
<p>Sounds important, doesn’t it? However, it’s like one of those “spend more quality time with your kids” things—important but easily squished in the priority list as you keep laying the next bit of track down.</p>
<p>One way I’ve made this kind of time is to <strong>prioritise creative activities.</strong></p>
<p>Once a month, I set off with no specific agenda in mind. I go to the museum. I head to an art gallery. I mooch through laneways looking at people and graffiti. I don’t go out to source blog ideas, fill my Instagram thread or look creative.</p>
<p>After using morning pages and meditation to regularly create some quiet brain space, <strong>I want to expose my mind to other ideas.</strong></p>
<p>There will <em>always</em> be more emails. There will <em>always</em> be a hot new marketing strategy you can implement. There will <em>always</em> be <a href="http://copywritematters.com/series/hot-copy-podcast/" target="_blank">podcasts</a> to listen to and blog posts to read (or create). These are just part of being a freelance copywriter and business owner.</p>
<p>But giving your brain new information and ideas <strong>also gives it more inputs to connect in quiet moments.</strong> Those unforced connections help you flex and strengthen your creative muscles.</p>
<h3>The results are cumulative</h3>
<p>By making regular time in your life to be creative, you’re more likely to slip into the smoking jacket of creativity more easily. It’s fun, too.</p>
<p>I know the results are cumulative because this process also works the other way. When you stop making time to let you brain recover from constant copywriting and run wild creatively (without structure) now and then, you begin to feel like you’re running out of track.</p>
<p>That’s where I am right now—almost out of track but looking forward to restocking over Christmas and rebooting my good habits.</p>
<h3>So how much time are we talking?</h3>
<p>Decluttering time, creative project time, life time…when you’re already busy (and aren’t we all), it can feel like there is <em>no more time</em> to spare.</p>
<p>So, let’s break it down.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>A daily brain declutter: 15–30 minutes</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>This is the time it might take you to have a cuppa. Just one cuppa a day to leave your brain fresh and uncluttered. </em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Project time: 1–2 hours for creative thinking on each copywriting project</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>Whether you sit down and work through a creative process or you just want to leave enough time to think in the shower, scheduling this time into your plan will mark your thinking time as valuable.</em></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><strong>Life time: Half a day, once a month</strong></p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>If you have no-work </em><em>weekends, fantastic (I do recommend them), but make time to do something that fills your creative well with new input. Four hours in 30 days? You can do that! </em></p>
<p>When you lay it out, that’s not a lot of time. At all.</p>
<p>Consider this post the kick up the bum we both need to value creative time.</p>
<p>It’s good for your brain, and it’s good for business. Creativity isn’t just about creating art. It can involve creative problem solving, creative strategies and of course creative writing.</p>
<p>So, how about you? How much time do you make to feed your creativity? Do you think it’s important? Or, is it a load of nonsense that successful business people don’t have time for?</p>
<p>I’d love to know your thoughts.</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/creative-well-running-dry-proven-tips-stimulate-creative-self-better-business/">Is your creative well running dry? Proven tips to stimulate your creative self for better business</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/creative-well-running-dry-proven-tips-stimulate-creative-self-better-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>12</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy podcast #37: Copywriting subcontracting – A ‘how to’ guide</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-subcontracting-guide/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-subcontracting-guide/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subcontracting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[subcontractor]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9442</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>In this week’s episode we’re talking about subcontracting. This is when a copywriter or agency uses someone else to write the copy. Generally they pass out the work and pay the writer a percentage of the overall fee. It’s something we get asked about a lot, as often, as your copywriting business grows, it can seem [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-subcontracting-guide/">Hot Copy podcast #37: Copywriting subcontracting – A ‘how to’ guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5440" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>In this week’s episode we’re talking about subcontracting. This is when a copywriter or agency uses someone else to write the copy. Generally they pass out the work and pay the writer a percentage of the overall fee.</p>
<p>It’s something we get asked about a lot, as often, as your copywriting business grows, it can seem like a great way to earn more money without actually writing copy.</p>
<p>But subcontracting can be problematic, and today we share our experiences and tips with you.</p>
<p><strong>Tune in to learn:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>The pros and cons of using subcontracting copywriters in your business</li>
<li>Belinda and Kate’s own experiences of using subcontractors</li>
<li>The pros and cons of being a subcontractor</li>
<li>Answers to the big subcontracting questions including:
<ul>
<li>Whether you can get a testimonial for work you did as a subcontractor?</li>
<li>Where you can use subcontracting work in your portfolio</li>
<li>The average margin charged on top of your rate</li>
<li>How much time you need to spend editing work from your subcontractors</li>
<li>Whether you have to disclose that you’re using a subcontractor</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>You can also listen on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/copywriting-subcontracting-a-how-to-guide" target="_blank">The Hot Copy podcast website</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If you like what you’re hearing on Hot Copy, the best way to support the show is to take just a few seconds to leave a rating and / or comment over on iTunes or Stitcher. Thanks!</p>
<p>We read out a review at the end of each show and today, we’re giving a shout out to larrye5012!</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Hotcopy-Meme-Template-1.png"><img class="aligncenter  wp-image-9441" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Hotcopy-Meme-Template-1.png" alt="Subcontracting meme" width="434" height="434" /></a></p>
<h3>Links mentioned in this article:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.ato.gov.au/business/employee-or-contractor/" target="_blank">ATO guide to employee or contractor</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.copywritingschool.com.au/shop/copywriting-subcontracting-agreement/" target="_blank">Sub contracting agreement</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-subcontracting-guide/">Hot Copy podcast #37: Copywriting subcontracting – A ‘how to’ guide</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-38-copywriting-subcontracting-guide/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot tips: Essential email follow-up strategies that win business!</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-tips-essential-email-follow-strategies-win-business/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-tips-essential-email-follow-strategies-win-business/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2016 20:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting tips]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[email marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[writing emails]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9427</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Email marketing has been the popular guest at the online marketing party for a long time now. Regardless of what people say, email is definitely NOT dead. It’s hard to write great emails that cut through the clutter of our inboxes, but at the 2016 Digital Commerce Summit, Brian Clark shared some stats indicating that [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-tips-essential-email-follow-strategies-win-business/">Hot tips: Essential email follow-up strategies that win business!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Emailfollowupblogimage.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-9434" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/Emailfollowupblogimage.png" alt="Email marketing follow up strategy: blog image" width="500" height="419" /></a></p>
<p>Email marketing has been the popular guest at the online marketing party for a long time now. Regardless of what people say, <strong>email is definitely NOT dead</strong>.</p>
<p>It’s hard to write great emails that cut through the clutter of our inboxes, but at the 2016 Digital Commerce Summit, Brian Clark shared some stats indicating that using email is a constant part of our lives, and millennials are no different. <a href="http://marketingland.com/speak-millennial-use-email-124811">This 2015 post from Marketing Land</a> says the same thing: young people are using email just as much as the rest of us.</p>
<p>So, when you want to reach out to people in a way that feels intimate and gets responses, <strong>write awesome emails</strong>.</p>
<p>But, once you write that email to a prospective copywriting client and actually hit send…then what?</p>
<p>You need to follow up, right? But how?</p>
<p>How you follow up on your email marketing can determine whether you get the business or the cold shoulder (or worse, the spam and block).</p>
<p>This post outlines some considerations and strategies for when you’re planning how to follow up on your email marketing campaigns.</p>
<p><span id="more-9427"></span></p>
<h3>Email marketing follow-up strategies</h3>
<p>Before you start stepping your reader through the ins and outs of your services, you must make sure you’re talking to the right person.</p>
<p>After all, your email campaign could be targeting:</p>
<ul>
<li>the wrong audience altogether.</li>
<li>the right audience but the wrong person.</li>
<li>the right audience and person but at the wrong time.</li>
<li>the right audience and person at the right time. SCORE!</li>
</ul>
<p>Let’s go through each of these scenarios and some lines you can use to quanlify your audience as part of your follow-up strategy.</p>
<p>Before we jump in,<strong> this process assumes that <a href="http://copywritematters.com/email-marketing-case-study/">you have written an awesome email</a> that identifies the challenges your readers are facing and gives them a good reason to talk to you.</strong></p>
<h3>The wrong email audience</h3>
<p>I recently got an email about some IT services. My name wasn’t used in the greeting (SPAM flag #1), it opened with the line “You create SEO strategies for your clients.” (I don’t; SPAM flag #2), the spelling and grammar weren’t great (SPAM flag #3) and it was full of technical jargon that I didn’t understand (overall FAIL).</p>
<p>I got three follow-up emails from this person before I replied explaining that I was clearly not the client he was looking for and asking him to take me off his list. This sender was <em>genuinely surprised</em>. He was not a deliberate spammer, but he was clearly targeting the wrong person, making his emails a wasted effort and an annoyance to me.</p>
<p>I suspect most people would have just marked his email as spam and blocked him as a sender. That result is a lot worse for your business than an ignored email!</p>
<h4>Email follow-up strategy</h4>
<p>When you email your prospective clients, ask them the following questions:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>“Is this a challenge you’re facing right now?”</em></p>
<p>Or even</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>“Is this something you’d be interested in chatting about some more?”</em></p>
<p>Consider including this line:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>“If not, just hit reply and let me know, and I’ll be sure not to bother you again.”</em></p>
<p>This will help you ascertain if you are targeting the right audience and help your audience feel empowered enough to stop you before you annoy them. And, it’s all very friendly and polite.</p>
<h3>The right email audience but the wrong person</h3>
<p>If you’re targeting someone within a corporation, it’s not only possible but likely that you won’t get the right person on your first email. It all depends on how well <a href="http://copywritematters.com/define-target-market/">you researched your target reader</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Finding the right person to talk to is essentia</strong>l when you’re promoting your services, as the wrong person won’t know about the challenges being faced and won’t care about your solution.</p>
<h4>Email follow-up strategy</h4>
<p>In your follow-up email, ask “Are you the best person to discuss this with? If not, could you perhaps let me know who is?”</p>
<p>Simple and to the point.</p>
<h3>The right email audience and person at the wrong time</h3>
<p>With any luck, you’ve done your research before emailing someone about your services. You’ve pegged him or her as being in your ideal customer audience, you’ve got the right person and you’ve greeted him or her by name.</p>
<p>GO YOU! #marketinghighfives</p>
<p><strong>But, he or she may not be ready to talk to you. </strong></p>
<p>He or she may be busy or may need to build a stronger relationship with you before being ready to commit.</p>
<p><em>Remember that hiring a copywriter (like you) to write the words that present a business to potential customers is a big deal. It requires trust, and building trust can take time.</em></p>
<h4>Email follow-up strategy</h4>
<p>After ascertaining your recipient is the right person, offer to chat with him or her about specific challenges and how you can help. But, leave an easy way to put you off for a while:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>“If I’ve caught you at a bad time, just let me know, and I’ll check back in a month’s time.”</em></p>
<p>Or get to know you a little more first:</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>“If improving the way you talk about your business (your copywriting) is on your radar, you might like to read some free copywriting tips on my blog. I also have this helpful page with tips on how to get the most out of working with a copywriter like myself.”</em></p>
<p>And when you follow up in a month’s time, you can say,</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;"><em>“I’m looking at my project calendar for the next month, and it’s filling up pretty fast. As we’ve been chatting about your copywriting needs, I want to make sure you are a priority booking.”</em></p>
<p>This works well when you’ve already sent <a href="http://copywritematters.com/copywriting-proposal-explosion/">a copywriting proposal</a>, but it can also work to give people a little nudge to have that first chat with you.</p>
<h3>The right email audience and person at the right time</h3>
<p>When this happens, you’ve struck GOLD! It’s time to take action!</p>
<p>That action might be sending a proposal (which requires its own follow-up strategy!) or sending a deposit and getting a <a href="http://copywritematters.com/the-secret-to-mindblowing-copywriting/">copywriting brief</a>!</p>
<p>Whichever it is, don’t dilly-dally!  If your awesome email marketing has worked and your potential client is ready to become a client, you cannot let them go cold on you.</p>
<h3>The point of it all</h3>
<p>Effective email marketing campaigns are <strong>well-researched</strong>, <strong>well-targeted</strong> and <strong>well-written</strong>. But, one email is rarely enough to encourage meaningful action.</p>
<p>An email follow-up strategy is essential, and it doesn’t have to feel like a hustle.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Be polite.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Show understanding.</p>
<p style="padding-left: 30px;">Be willing to give your reader the space he or she needs to say yes.</p>
<p>I hope these tips have been useful. Let me know if they have been. Or, perhaps you have your own follow-up ninja tricks. If you do, share them here!</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-tips-essential-email-follow-strategies-win-business/">Hot tips: Essential email follow-up strategies that win business!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-tips-essential-email-follow-strategies-win-business/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>4</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy FLASHBACK: How to find copywriting clients</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-flashback-find-copywriting-clients/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-flashback-find-copywriting-clients/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2016 23:00:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting clients]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot copy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9409</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>This week we&#8217;re stepping back in time to revisit one of our all time favourite pods &#8211; and by the look of the stats one of your faves too. It&#8217;s all very good and well to understand how to use modal verbs and where to place your colons, but seriously the hard fact is that no [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-flashback-find-copywriting-clients/">Hot Copy FLASHBACK: How to find copywriting clients</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5440" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p>This week we&#8217;re stepping back in time to revisit one of our all time favourite pods &#8211; and by the look of the stats one of your faves too.</p>
<p>It&#8217;s all very good and well to understand how to use modal verbs and where to place your colons, but seriously the hard fact is that no copywriting business will survive without CLIENTS!!</p>
<p>Sadly too many copywriting businesses fail in their first year because they simply can’t find enough clients.</p>
<p>Friends and family are a great place to start, but where on earth do you track down awesome potential clients with money to spend?</p>
<p>So we thought it was a good idea to circle back around and revisit this pod and remind of our tips on how to grab more clients.</p>
<p><strong>Tune in to learn:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li>Our key ways to find clients</li>
<li>Whether freelancing websites are worth the effort</li>
<li>Our number one new client tip</li>
</ul>
<p><iframe style="border: none;" src="//html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/4715213/height/360/width/640/theme/standard/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/autoplay/no/preload/no/no_addthis/no/direction/backward/no-cache/true/" width="292" height="292" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>You can also listen on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/flashback-how-to-find-copywriting-clients-2" target="_blank">The Hot Copy podcast website</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If you like what you’re hearing on Hot Copy, the best way to support the show is to take just a few seconds to leave a rating and / or comment over on iTunes or Stitcher. Thanks!</p>
<p>We read out a review at the end of each show and today, we’re giving a shout out (and virtual hugs) to Robert Gerrish for his review!</p>
<h3>Useful Links:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.rachelslist.com.au/" target="_blank">Rachel’s list</a></li>
<li><a href="http://jobs.problogger.net/" target="_blank">Problogger job board</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.copywritingschool.com.au/jobs" target="_blank">Clever Copywriting School job board</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.upwork.com/" target="_blank">Upwork </a>(previously odesk)</li>
<li><a href="https://www.elance.com/" target="_blank">Elance</a></li>
<li><a href="https://plus.google.com/u/0/communities/108690994474126440326" target="_blank">Freelancer community on Google+</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-flashback-find-copywriting-clients/">Hot Copy FLASHBACK: How to find copywriting clients</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-flashback-find-copywriting-clients/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Want FREE expert advice on a successful product launch?</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/launch-with-partners-summit-2016/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/launch-with-partners-summit-2016/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2016 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9362</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>What if you could sit down face to face with Neil Patel, Danny Iny, Bushra Azhar, Tom Morkes, Navid Moazzez, Liam Austin, Stephen Esketzis, Jon Schumacher and other world-class experts? Including me! Imagine how many valuable insights you could get from just 15 minutes… What if I could give you more than 15 minutes and [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/launch-with-partners-summit-2016/">Want FREE expert advice on a successful product launch?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/FacebookBelindaWeaver.png"><img class="aligncenter size-large wp-image-9363" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/10/FacebookBelindaWeaver-1024x536.png" alt="Launch with Partners Summit header" width="1024" height="536" /></a></p>
<p>What if you could sit down face to face with Neil Patel, Danny Iny, Bushra Azhar, Tom Morkes, Navid Moazzez, Liam Austin, Stephen Esketzis, Jon Schumacher and other world-class experts?</p>
<p>Including me!</p>
<p>Imagine how many valuable insights you could get from just 15 minutes…</p>
<h4>What if I could give you more than 15 minutes and for FREE?</h4>
<p>What if? What if? What if?</p>
<p>Well, I was recently invited to participate in a rather amazing online summit all about launching online products, <em>successfully</em>. The 10 day summit has 30 experts in their fields share the latest strategies on finding great partners, create your winning strategy and position yourself for launch success.</p>
<p>This is not just another virtual summit with a lot of interviews on unrelated topics that you should somehow put together and implement on your own.</p>
<p>Instead, <strong>this is a carefully curated 10-day crash course on launching your product online, even if your email list is tiny (or non-existent).</strong></p>
<p>Since I’m a speaker I’ve lined up a FREE ticket for you.</p>
<p><a href="https://brainartllc.simplero.com/products/51665-Premium-Pass-Launch-With-Partners?ref=8644-Belinda-Weaver">Grab your FREE PASS here</a></p>
<p><strong>My presentation shares my tips on writing copy that sells your product <em>before</em> you launch (so you sell out when you launch).</strong></p>
<p>I walk through my strategy for creating buzz around my sell-out <a href="http://copywritematters.com/learn-copywriting-course/">Copywriting Master Class</a>. Which hasn&#8217;t just sold out once. It&#8217;s sold out <em>five times</em>. As I&#8217;ve only run the course six times, I think that&#8217;s a good result.</p>
<p>And I&#8217;m just one speaker out of thirty.</p>
<p><a href="https://brainartllc.simplero.com/products/51665-Premium-Pass-Launch-With-Partners?ref=8644-Belinda-Weaver" target="_blank">Click here to grab your FREE Pass before it all starts</a>.</p>
<p>Over these 10 days in October you can also</p>
<p>&#8230;listen to Danny Iny do a deep-dive into how he started with a handful of potential partners and building up to a business that brings in multiple millions in annual revenue&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8230;and Neil Patel explain how he got his book deal worth $500,000 upfront&#8230;</p>
<p>&#8230;and learn from Rich German as he explains the magic question which could bring you more and more partners to help you with your launch&#8230;</p>
<p><strong>You have 48 hours to to view each session for FREE.<br />
</strong>Or <a href="http://smpl.ro/al/NfmPPMhHN4UVKwsqYVyJepSA/8644-Belinda-Weaver" target="_blank">upgrade to a premium pass</a> and keep all the sessions plus get tonnes of extra bonuses.</p>
<p>After you attend Launch with Partners Crash Course you’ll know how to find great partners, create your winning strategy and position yourself for launch success.</p>
<h3>When does it start?</h3>
<p><strong>October 17</strong> is Day 0, when Launch with Partners 10-Day Crash Course kicks off.</p>
<p>It all wraps up on October 28.</p>
<p>30 speakers giving your over 20 hours of high quality expertise, worth well over $10,000.</p>
<p><a href="https://brainartllc.simplero.com/products/51665-Premium-Pass-Launch-With-Partners?ref=8644-Belinda-Weaver" target="_blank">Find out more about the speakers and the summit program And grab your FREE Pass before it all starts</a>.</p>
<h3>Fancy a free launch playbook to whet your whistle?</h3>
<p>If you&#8217;re not quite ready to sign up for a free pass, Ciprian has created a <b>Launch with Partners Playbook.</b> The Playbook isn’t just a guide to the crash course; it’s also a cheat sheet for what YOU can do to skyrocket your product launch right away.</p>
<p><a href="http://smpl.ro/al/xMexgAReMKhAiqbvNDCTAN4N/8644-Belinda-Weaver" target="_blank">Grab the free playbook </a></p>
<p>So. Much. Free.</p>
<p>I will definitely be tuning into the other sessions!</p>
<p>See you there?</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>P.S. I mentioned a Premium Pass up there. It&#8217;s reduced from $297 USD to $97 USD for a limited time (only until Sept 23) and includes:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p class="ttfm6 bold_text">Lifetime access to 30 expert sessions VIDEO + MP3 audio recordings for your convenience (<span style="color: #f05037;">$10,000 Value</span>)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="ttfm6 bold_text">30 Launch with Partners Actionable MindMaps (<span style="color: #f05037;">$997 Value</span>) &#8211; for the visual thinkers</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="ttfm6 bold_text">Special deals and discounts worth <span style="color: #f05037;">$3,300</span></p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="ttfm6 bold_text">Special bonuses from our experts to jumpstart your launch immediately (<span style="color: #f05037;">$8,356 value</span>)</p>
</li>
<li>
<p class="ttfm6 bold_text">Launch with Partners Mastermind Community (<span style="color: #f05037;">$997 value</span>)</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>The bonus I am giving is the first lesson in my Copywriting Master Class, teaching you how to identify the motives of your target audience. And other speakers are giving just as generously.</p>
<p><a href="http://smpl.ro/al/NfmPPMhHN4UVKwsqYVyJepSA/8644-Belinda-Weaver" target="_blank">Upgrade to premium now</a></p>
<p>P.P.S The links here are affiliate links but you don&#8217;t have to use them <img src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-includes/images/smilies/simple-smile.png" alt=":)" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/launch-with-partners-summit-2016/">Want FREE expert advice on a successful product launch?</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/launch-with-partners-summit-2016/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy podcast #36: 6 essential ways to market your copywriting business &#8211; Part 2</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-36-essentials-marketing-part2/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-36-essentials-marketing-part2/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2016 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[copywriting]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot copy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9300</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Finally, part two! &#160; We’re at the second half of our two-part episode on marketing your copywriting business. Marketing gets the message out that are in business so it really is essential but what should you spend your time on? Tune in to part two to learn about: Running your own events Content marketing to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-36-essentials-marketing-part2/">Hot Copy podcast #36: 6 essential ways to market your copywriting business &#8211; Part 2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Finally, part two!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter size-medium wp-image-5440" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">We’re at the second half of our two-part episode on marketing your copywriting business. Marketing gets the message out that are in business so it really is essential but what should you spend your time on?</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Tune in to part two to learn about:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Running your own events</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Content marketing to develop yourself as an authority</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Our best tips to succeed at your content marketing</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Email marketing – what you need to know</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">Don’t forget that in part 1 we also covered:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">The importance of branding and how to make yours work hard</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Social media marketing</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Networking (on and offline)</span></li>
</ul>
<p><iframe style="border: none;" src="//html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/4685281/height/360/width/640/theme/standard-mini/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/autoplay/no/preload/no/no_addthis/no/direction/backward/no-cache/true/" width="366" height="366" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe><br />
You can also listen on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/6-essential-ways-to-market-your-copywriting-business-part-2" target="_blank">The Hot Copy podcast website</a></li>
</ul>
<p>If you like what you’re hearing on Hot Copy, the best way to support the show is to take just a few seconds to leave a rating and / or comment over on iTunes or Stitcher. Thanks!</p>
<p>We read out a review at the end of each show and today, we’re giving a shout out to Kate Merriweather for her super review!</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/marketing-tips-for-copywriters.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-9299" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/09/marketing-tips-for-copywriters.png" alt="Hot Copy marketing meme" width="499" height="499" /></a></p>
<h3>Useful Links:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/podcast-28-blog-youre-just-starting/"><u>Podcast 28: New copywriter’s guide to blogging</u></a></li>
<li><a href="http://copywritematters.com/blog-or-email-newsletter/"><u>Blog or email newsletter—Which is better for business?</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/how-to-spring-clean-your-blog/"><u>How to spring-clean your blog</u></a></li>
<li><a href="http://copywritematters.com/3-tragic-email-mistakes/"><u>3 tragic email mistakes that are costing you business</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/email-unsubscribes-my-top-nine-tactics/"><u>Email unsubscribes: My top nine tactics</u></a></li>
<li><a href="http://copywritematters.com/email-marketing-copywriting-tips/"><u>Email marketing: This copywriter’s playbook on getting emails noticed, read and actioned</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/perfect-email-6-deployment/"><u>How to build the perfect email: Deployment</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/how-to-build-the-perfect-email-part-5-code/"><u>How to build the perfect email: Code</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/perfect-email-part-4-design/"><u>How to build the perfect email: Design</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/how-to-build-the-perfect-email-copy/"><u>How to build the perfect email: Copy</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/perfect-email-part-3-copy/"><u>How to build the perfect email: Copy 2</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/perfect-email-strategy/"><u>How to build the perfect email: Strategy</u></a></li>
<li><a href="http://copywritematters.com/email-marketing-case-study/"><u>Email marketing case study: Lessons of seduction</u></a></li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-36-essentials-marketing-part2/">Hot Copy podcast #36: 6 essential ways to market your copywriting business &#8211; Part 2</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-36-essentials-marketing-part2/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why the competition is YOUR fault</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/competition-fault/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/competition-fault/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business Stuff]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competition]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competitive advantage]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[competitor]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[customer service]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.copywritematters.com.au/?p=3445</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>When your clients go to the competitors, it’s your fault. That’s right. I first heard that statement in Scott Stratten’s Unmarketing podcast and it’s been knocking around in my brain ever since. I mean, what about the idea of competitors coming in and stealing your business? Making special offers that woo your clients over to [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/competition-fault/">Why the competition is YOUR fault</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<figure id="attachment_5673" style="width: 302px;" class="wp-caption aligncenter"><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/Shocked-Man.jpg"><img class="wp-image-5673" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/02/Shocked-Man.jpg" alt="A shocked copywriter" width="302" height="453" /></a><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">You read that right. Your. Fault.</figcaption></figure>
<p>When your clients go to the competitors, it’s your fault.</p>
<p><strong>That’s right.</strong></p>
<p>I first heard that statement in Scott Stratten’s <a href="http://www.unmarketing.com/category/podcast/" target="_blank"><em>Unmarketing</em> podcast</a> and it’s been knocking around in my brain ever since.</p>
<p>I mean, what about the idea of competitors coming in and <em>stealing</em> your business? Making special offers that woo your clients over to their side of the fence?</p>
<p>The unfairness of it all.</p>
<p>The simple truth is that if you aren’t being awesome enough all the time, <strong>your clients are fair game and they <em>should</em> look elsewhere.</strong></p>
<p>In this particular episode Scott talked about Air Canada, saying, “You had the hardest part done. I was a customer. I was a loyal customer, and I was part of your loyalty program, and I left. That is solely and absolutely only Air Canada&#8217;s fault. That was not because WestJet was good or better.”</p>
<p>So what can you do to make sure your clients aren’t seduced by your competitors?</p>
<p><span id="more-3445"></span></p>
<h2>1. Make sure you communicate with your clients, regularly.</h2>
<p>That means (gasp) talking to them:</p>
<ul>
<li>As they enquire about your services <em>(to show them what else is possible)</em></li>
<li>As they make their decision <em>(to guide them towards YES)</em></li>
<li>Once they lock you in <em>(so they know what happens next)</em></li>
<li>As you work <em>(so they know when to expect to hear from you)</em></li>
<li>After you’ve delivered <em>(so they remember you for the next job)</em></li>
</ul>
<p>That sounds like a lot of communication, doesn’t it?</p>
<p>You don’t need to <em>bombard</em> clients but you also don’t want your potential and existing clients to wonder where you got to. Or worse yet, forget about you!</p>
<p>Kate and I bang on about this all the time on our own <a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/" target="_blank">Hot Copy podcast</a>: Have a systematic process through your projects, including your communication with clients.</p>
<p>Setting expectations is critical to positive customer satisfaction because the more uncertain your client is, the more anxious they are. And the more dissatisfied they will be, regardless of how good your copywriting is. I guarantee it.</p>
<p>You should also keep in touch through <a title="Blog or email newsletter—Which is better for business?" href="http://copywritematters.com/blog-or-email-newsletter/">newsletters and blogs</a>, <a title="Email marketing case study: Lessons of seduction" href="http://copywritematters.com/email-marketing-case-study/">email marketing</a> (and not just about your latest promotion) or stay connected by being active on social media.</p>
<p><strong>Respond. Engage. Talk.</strong></p>
<h2>2. Listen</h2>
<p>You’d think that listening would be part of communicating but it’s the part so many businesses skip. It’s easy to get so caught up in the sending that you stop listening for replies.</p>
<p>Many unsatisfied clients will just leave and <strong>you will never even know</strong>.</p>
<p>As a customer, I don’t waste my time trying to get justice… I simply walk away and never come back. Ok. That’s not entirely true. I walk away and never come back and sometimes,  I also tell everyone I know.</p>
<p>When you’re very engaged with your client base you will be able to catch those people before they go. In many cases, you won’t.</p>
<p>A lot of clients will try and tell you they aren’t happy – <em>if you listen</em>.</p>
<p><strong>Invite regular comments and feedback</strong> from clients and <strong>make it easy and inviting</strong> for them to respond. <strong>Pay attention</strong> to what they say and <strong>make an action plan</strong> to improve how you work.</p>
<p><strong>Look at your email open rates.</strong> Are they even interested enough to click?</p>
<p>If you send a survey to gauge satisfaction, <strong>focus on just one issue</strong> to make your survey super short.</p>
<p>If you suspect they are finding how you work confusing or challenging, <strong>don’t be too busy to check in</strong> and help them. And improve your process so other clients don&#8217;t suffer the same confusion.</p>
<h2>3. Solve real problems</h2>
<p>This is at the heart of what we do, isn’t it? <strong>We create businesses to solve problems for people.</strong></p>
<p>Your clients might come to you to solve big hairy problems or niggling dissatisfactions. Always <strong>dig into the triggers and motivations</strong> that are driving them to act and work out how you can <strong>be part of the solution.</strong></p>
<p>Sometimes, that means sending clients to your competitors because they are the better business for the job. You might be surprised at how many clients come back simply because you had the courage to admit that you couldn’t be part of the solution – but you knew someone who could.</p>
<h2>4. Make it easy to do business with you</h2>
<p>When a new client signs up for a project I ask them to fill out a form and give me some information about their business – their postal address, ABN/ACN, contact details for the project liaison, etc.</p>
<p>I used to ask for all the social media links as well but I took those off. Why? Because in 95% of cases, I already had that information. So I was asking new clients to type it in as a time saver for <em>me</em>.</p>
<p><em>That wasn’t making life easier for my clients!</em></p>
<p>Systems, processes and approvals are all very good. Checks and balances are great to help you deliver consistent service but if they become a roadblock to actually delivering good service and getting the job done, <strong>they will work against you.</strong></p>
<p>Who else has raged at lines like, “I’ll have to get my manager to approve this.” Or “Enter your account number”… AGAIN?!? That’s what I’m talking about.</p>
<p>When you make it hard to do business with you, you are creating a slow drip of dissatisfaction. <strong>That’s exactly what your competitors <em>should</em> take advantage of.</strong></p>
<h2>5. See every moment as a chance to be awesome</h2>
<p>Every time a potential, existing and past client contacts you – for any reason – that’s when <strong>you have to be awesome.</strong></p>
<p>When you get an enquiry about new business. For marketing interviews to share your business and cheeky requests for free advice. When you’re feeling like you can conquer the world. When you’re tired and cranky. To super duper clients and the tricky ones. When it’s your fault and when it’s not. <a title="Be awesome in difficult moments" href="http://copywritematters.com/awesome-difficult-moments/">Especially when it’s not your fault</a>.</p>
<p>We’re all human and I think it’s fair to say that <strong>it’s damn hard work delivering awesome customer service 100% of the time.</strong> But when awesome is your default, the slips are easily forgiven.</p>
<p>Then even when your competitors start sharing incredible deals and cut price promotions, your clients will say, “Nah, I’m good.”</p>
<p><strong>They will have your back because you’ve got theirs.</strong> And that isn’t about group hugs. It translates to your bottom line.</p>
<p>So now I throw this open. Do you agree? What great client-keeping tips can you share?</p>
<p><em>The Copy Detective</em></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/competition-fault/">Why the competition is YOUR fault</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/competition-fault/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>14</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hot Copy podcast #35: 6 essential ways to market your copywriting business &#8211; Part 1</title>
		<link>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-35-essentials-marketing-part1/</link>
		<comments>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-35-essentials-marketing-part1/#respond</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 22 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Belinda Weaver]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Hot Copy podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[hot copy]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[marketing]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[podcast]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://copywritematters.com/?p=9257</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to another bloggy interruption of pod love&#8230; If you don’t market yourself as a copywriter, you won’t get many clients and without clients, you aren’t in business! So we’re tackling the essential ways to market your copywriting business to make sure you stay in business. This is a big topic so we’ve broken it [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-35-essentials-marketing-part1/">Hot Copy podcast #35: 6 essential ways to market your copywriting business &#8211; Part 1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to another bloggy interruption of pod love&#8230;</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-e1442870649872.jpg"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-5440 size-medium" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/HotCopy_iTunes-300x300.jpg" alt="Hot Copy copywriting podcast logo" width="300" height="300" /></a></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">If you don’t market yourself as a copywriter, you won’t get many clients and without clients, you aren’t in business! So we’re tackling the essential ways to market your copywriting business to make sure you stay in business.</span></p>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">This is a big topic so we’ve broken it into two episodes. Our very first two parter!</span></p>
<p><strong><span style="color: #000000;">Tune in to part one to learn about:</span></strong></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Our favourite parts of marketing ourselves and our writing</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">The importance of branding and how to make yours work hard</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Our best branding tips</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Social media marketing</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Our experiences and best tips</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Networking (on and offline)</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Our favourite networking events and our tips to rock it!</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">In part two of this episode we’ll cover:</span></p>
<ul>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Running events as an authority</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Content marketing to develop yourself as an authority</span></li>
<li><span style="color: #000000;">Email marketing</span></li>
</ul>
<p><span style="color: #000000;">So there’s more good stuff coming!</span></p>
<p><iframe style="border: none;" src="//html5-player.libsyn.com/embed/episode/id/4685219/height/360/width/640/theme/standard-mini/autonext/no/thumbnail/yes/autoplay/no/preload/no/no_addthis/no/direction/backward/no-cache/true/" width="640" height="360" scrolling="no" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen"></iframe></p>
<p>Find us on:</p>
<ul>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/podcast/hot-copy-podcast/id1015210035">iTunes</a></li>
<li><a style="color: #c95533;" href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://www.stitcher.com/s?fid=69196&amp;refid=stpr">Stitcher</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Or head to the <a href="http://www.hotcopypodcast.com/6-essential-ways-market-copywriting-business-1" target="_blank">Hot Copy podcast website</a>!</p>
<p>If you like what you’re hearing on Hot Copy, the best way to support the show is to take just a few seconds to leave a rating and / or comment over on iTunes or Stitcher. Thanks!</p>
<p>We read out a review at the end of each show and today, we’re giving a shout out to Raegen Perkins for an excellent review left on Stitcher!</p>
<p><a href="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Hotcopy-Meme-TemplatePT1.png"><img class="aligncenter wp-image-9259" src="http://copywritematters.com/wp-content/uploads/2016/08/Hotcopy-Meme-TemplatePT1.png" alt="It's our MEME! Display images to see it." width="501" height="501" /></a></p>
<h3>Useful Links:</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/the-shocking-truth-about-my-branding/"><u>The shocking truth about my branding</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/corporate-headshots-does-your-image-matter/"><u>Corporate headshots: Does your image matter?</u></a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.katetooncopywriter.com.au/social-media-marketing-made-easy/"><u>Social Media Marketing Made Easy</u></a></li>
<li><a href="http://copywritematters.com/quick-social-graphics/"><u>How to create all your social media graphics in less than 2 hours per month</u></a></li>
<li><a href="http://copywritematters.com/nail-your-social-media-in-5-minutes/"><u>Nail your social media in just 5 minutes a day. Seriously</u></a>.</li>
<li><a href="http://copywritematters.com/offline-network-real-life/"><u>Get offline. Go and network in real life!</u></a></li>
</ul>
<p>Enjoy!</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-35-essentials-marketing-part1/">Hot Copy podcast #35: 6 essential ways to market your copywriting business &#8211; Part 1</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="http://copywritematters.com">Copywrite Matters</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://copywritematters.com/hot-copy-podcast-35-essentials-marketing-part1/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
